<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-12-07T07:57:38-08:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">A Little Ludwig Goes a Long Way</title><entry><title type="html">My Top 6 Books</title><link href="/blog/top-five" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Top 6 Books" /><published>2022-11-25T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-11-25T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>/blog/top-five</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/top-five">&lt;p&gt;Bill Gates recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatesnotes.com/About-Bill-Gates/Holiday-Books-2022&quot;&gt;posted some of his favorite books&lt;/a&gt;.  And it has inspired me to think about my all time favorites.  I have 1200+ books listed on Goodreads and I am sure there are another 500-1000 I’ve read that I have never put on Goodreads (for instance, I read every Allen Drury political drama back in my teens, loved them, but I’ve never bothered to put on Goodreads).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I narrowed my list down to 6 with some alternates as well.  (Sorry I couldn’t get to 5, Bill is better at this than I am)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/378.The_Phantom_Tollbooth&quot;&gt;The Phantom Tollbooth&lt;/a&gt; by Norton Juster with illustrations by Jules Feiffer.  This book hooked me on reading as a young reader, I loved the story and the wordplay.  It is probably not a great adult book read but I think it is fabulous for young readers.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17157681-the-hobbit-part-one&quot;&gt;The Hobbit&lt;/a&gt; is of course a great choice as well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/112537.Rendezvous_with_Rama&quot;&gt;Rendezvous with Rama&lt;/a&gt; by Arthur C. Clarke.  I read a ton of classic science fiction and I loved much of it.  Rama really had a sense of mystery and wonder that I enjoyed.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/234225.Dune&quot;&gt;Dune&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/77566.Hyperion&quot;&gt;Hyperion&lt;/a&gt; are great books in the genre as well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18423.The_Left_Hand_of_Darkness&quot;&gt;The Left Hand of Darkness&lt;/a&gt; by Ursula K. Leguin.  I love all of Leguin’s works, this book showed me that speculative fiction could be so much deeper.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/334176.The_Sparrow&quot;&gt;The Sparrow&lt;/a&gt; is an excellent choice too.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1138543.The_Strange_Death_of_Liberal_England&quot;&gt;The Strange Death of Liberal England&lt;/a&gt; by George Dangerfield.  One of my favorite history books about a period of great change, just so well written. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1128055.Hitler_s_Thirty_Days_to_Power&quot;&gt;Hitler’s Thirty Days to Power&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/50159458-kent-state&quot;&gt;Kent State: Four Dead in Ohio&lt;/a&gt; are excellent choices as well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/262304.The_Wild_Party&quot;&gt;The Wild Party&lt;/a&gt; by Joseph Moncure March with illustrations by Art Spiegelman.  A quirky little piece of fiction that I find incredibly entertaining.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11149.The_Screwtape_Letters&quot;&gt;The Screwtape Letters&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/19288259-dear-committee-members&quot;&gt;Dear Committee Members&lt;/a&gt; are fun choices too.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/54218.The_Mismeasure_of_Man&quot;&gt;The Mismeasure of Man&lt;/a&gt; by Stephen Jay Gould.  All of Gould’s work is excellent, this set of analyses is well argued and well written.  Other good non-fiction choices are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13629.The_Mythical_Man_Month&quot;&gt;The Mythical Man-Month&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/35187180-the-death-and-life-of-the-great-lakes&quot;&gt;The Death and Life of the Great Lakes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11721966-good-strategy-bad-strategy&quot;&gt;Good Strategy, Bad Strategy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/242472.The_Black_Swan&quot;&gt;The Black Swan&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17884043-tune-in&quot;&gt;Tune In&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Bill Gates recently posted some of his favorite books. And it has inspired me to think about my all time favorites. I have 1200+ books listed on Goodreads and I am sure there are another 500-1000 I’ve read that I have never put on Goodreads (for instance, I read every Allen Drury political drama back in my teens, loved them, but I’ve never bothered to put on Goodreads).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Knight Series, Pyramid of Lies, Spin, The Secret History</title><link href="/blog/knight" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Knight Series, Pyramid of Lies, Spin, The Secret History" /><published>2022-11-18T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-11-18T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>/blog/knight</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/knight">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/56985443-her-name-is-knight&quot;&gt;Her Name Is Knight&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/59132250-they-come-at-knight&quot;&gt;They Come At Knight&lt;/a&gt; by Yasmin Angoe.  The first book is a good start to a thriller series featuring a young African assassin who has been thru a hellacious early life, and is now starting to avenge herself.  The tale continues int he second book, which loses its way for a little while, although ends well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/61640141-the-pyramid-of-lies&quot;&gt;The Pyramid of Lies: Lex Greensill and the Billion-Dollar Scandal&lt;/a&gt; by Duncan Mavin.  More detail than I really wanted on this scandal.  I am excited to read the equivalent about Sam Bankman-Fried some day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/59028343-spin&quot;&gt;Spin&lt;/a&gt; by Robert Charles Wilson.  Great tale of three close friends who deal with the transformation of Earth by alien technologies.  Great characters dealing with stress.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29044.The_Secret_History&quot;&gt;The Secret History&lt;/a&gt; by Donna Tartt.  This book seems well written, but the characters are unpleasant and the situation is unpleasant and I just didn’t enjoy putting this into my head.  Moving on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Her Name Is Knight, They Come At Knight by Yasmin Angoe. The first book is a good start to a thriller series featuring a young African assassin who has been thru a hellacious early life, and is now starting to avenge herself. The tale continues int he second book, which loses its way for a little while, although ends well. The Pyramid of Lies: Lex Greensill and the Billion-Dollar Scandal by Duncan Mavin. More detail than I really wanted on this scandal. I am excited to read the equivalent about Sam Bankman-Fried some day. Spin by Robert Charles Wilson. Great tale of three close friends who deal with the transformation of Earth by alien technologies. Great characters dealing with stress. The Secret History by Donna Tartt. This book seems well written, but the characters are unpleasant and the situation is unpleasant and I just didn’t enjoy putting this into my head. Moving on.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – American and Iran, Toaster Project, Foundryside, Freezing Order, Nazi Billionaires</title><link href="/blog/american-and-iran" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – American and Iran, Toaster Project, Foundryside, Freezing Order, Nazi Billionaires" /><published>2022-10-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/blog/american-and-iran</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/american-and-iran">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/49201929-america-and-iran&quot;&gt;America and Iran: A History 1720 to the Present&lt;/a&gt; by John Ghazvinian.  This has been a long read, and an exceptional read.  So much I didn’t know.  Heartbreaking, so much ill will and bad behaviour between the countries, serving no one’s purpose.  Such opportunity lost.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18904629-the-toaster-project&quot;&gt;The Toaster Project: Or A Heroic Attempt to Build a Simple Electric Appliance from Scratch&lt;/a&gt; by Thomas Thwaites.  A very short book documenting this project. Reminds you of just how advanced and specialized and interconnected our society is; the days of living along off the land are long gone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/37173847-foundryside&quot;&gt;Foundryside&lt;/a&gt; by Robert Jackson Bennett.  Quite entertaining fantasy romp.  A young thief gains access to magical secrets and upends the power structure of a country.  Good characters.  First of a series and I’m sure I’d enjoy the rest, tho this works very well on its own.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60399061-freezing-order&quot;&gt;Freezing Order: A True Story of Money Laundering, Murder, and Surviving Vladimir Putin’s Wrath&lt;/a&gt; by Bill Browder.  A pretty exciting tale about money laundering and the attempts to fight it over the last 2 decades.  A very dangerous fight.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60842883-nazi-billionaires&quot;&gt;Nazi Billionaires: The Dark History of Germany’s Wealthiest Dynasties&lt;/a&gt; by David de Jong.  A long retelling of the wealth of some of Germany’s richest people, and how many of these families benefitted from Nazi ties.  The book kind of loses its way in the flood of never ending details and maybe that is the point – the ties to the Nazis were pervasive, and never really resolved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">America and Iran: A History 1720 to the Present by John Ghazvinian. This has been a long read, and an exceptional read. So much I didn’t know. Heartbreaking, so much ill will and bad behaviour between the countries, serving no one’s purpose. Such opportunity lost. The Toaster Project: Or A Heroic Attempt to Build a Simple Electric Appliance from Scratch by Thomas Thwaites. A very short book documenting this project. Reminds you of just how advanced and specialized and interconnected our society is; the days of living along off the land are long gone. Foundryside by Robert Jackson Bennett. Quite entertaining fantasy romp. A young thief gains access to magical secrets and upends the power structure of a country. Good characters. First of a series and I’m sure I’d enjoy the rest, tho this works very well on its own. Freezing Order: A True Story of Money Laundering, Murder, and Surviving Vladimir Putin’s Wrath by Bill Browder. A pretty exciting tale about money laundering and the attempts to fight it over the last 2 decades. A very dangerous fight. Nazi Billionaires: The Dark History of Germany’s Wealthiest Dynasties by David de Jong. A long retelling of the wealth of some of Germany’s richest people, and how many of these families benefitted from Nazi ties. The book kind of loses its way in the flood of never ending details and maybe that is the point – the ties to the Nazis were pervasive, and never really resolved.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">3 features I’d like in streaming media</title><link href="/blog/streaming" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="3 features I’d like in streaming media" /><published>2022-10-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/blog/streaming</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/streaming">&lt;p&gt;1, I really wish the AppleTV device had features for serious sports viewers.  PIP so I can keep up with multiple games.  Fast 1-button switching between two or three different games.  I used to have these features on my old cable boxes, we have really lost something.  And sports enthusiasts would pay for these features, if there was a special sports version of the appletv box I would buy it in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2, I’d love to see my viewing history for any service as I can with Netflix (although even on Netflix, it is buried in a stupid place in the UX).  I’d like to be able to quickly rate shows, filter my history, share it or a filtered subset of it, etc.  Every week my kids ask me “what did you watch good this week?” and I have to scramble to answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3, I wish all streaming services would integrate with either/both AppleTV and Amazon aggregation features - easy account activation/deactivation, viewing within the app, participation in favorites list, etc.  I want to use an aggregator and I don’t care which one particularly.  I don’t want to have 17 logins with 17 different apps with 17 different UXes – and boy are the UXes on some of the lesser streaming services bad, Showtime I’m looking at you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">1, I really wish the AppleTV device had features for serious sports viewers. PIP so I can keep up with multiple games. Fast 1-button switching between two or three different games. I used to have these features on my old cable boxes, we have really lost something. And sports enthusiasts would pay for these features, if there was a special sports version of the appletv box I would buy it in seconds.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Optimism</title><link href="/blog/optimism" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Optimism" /><published>2022-10-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/blog/optimism</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/optimism">&lt;p&gt;It is easy to be concerned about the nation and the world.  So much bad news and misbehavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wow, do I feel optimistic this week.  Like so many people I’ve been playing around with &lt;a href=&quot;https://stability.ai&quot;&gt;Stable Diffusion&lt;/a&gt;, and to a lesser extent Midjourney and Dall-E 2. Tons of fun, the open nature of Stable Diffusion makes it easy to play with, I’m reminded of how much fun it was the first time I got a PC.  And the rate of innovation around it is incredible – a &lt;a href=&quot;https://keras.io/guides/keras_cv/generate_images_with_stable_diffusion/&quot;&gt;KerasCV port&lt;/a&gt; which seems super fast, alternative web UIs like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AUTOMATIC1111/stable-diffusion-webui&quot;&gt;Automatic1111&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/deforum/stable-diffusion&quot;&gt;animation&lt;/a&gt; aupport, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nateraw/stable-diffusion-videos&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; applications, tools to do incremental training for new objects and styles, prompt generation tools, landscape generation tools, inpainting, outpainting, masking, mosaicing, audio equivalents – it is hard to keep up with everything.  Incredibly exciting time, great energy.  Lots of issues around copyright and IP protection to be figured out, but still super exciting.  I like &lt;a href=&quot;https://lspace.swyx.io/p/multiverse-not-metaverse&quot;&gt;this phrasing&lt;/a&gt; – the creative multiverse is way more exciting than some corporate metaverse.  Stable Diffusion and its kin are going to be major accelerants for every creative task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I see reasons for great optimism outside software.  I am relatively stupid about things biologic, but I get pretty excited when I read articles like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tsungxu.com/performance-biomaterials&quot;&gt;Biomanufactured Materials Are Coming&lt;/a&gt;.  Imagine if we can create Moore’s Law equivalents for biologic materials – ever cheaper, ever higher volume, ever more function biologics – the applications are pretty endless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then look at the space industry – &lt;a href=&quot;https://brycetech.com/reports/report-documents/Bryce_Briefing_2022_Q2.pdf&quot;&gt;Launch volumes are going way up, costs are going way down&lt;/a&gt;.  And there are a ton of companies working hard to make this happen faster – for instance &lt;a href=&quot;stokespace.com&quot;&gt;Stoke Space&lt;/a&gt;.  Getting the free market to work on this challenge has been brilliant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could probably get just as excited about the declining cost of renewable energy and the implications of much cheaper energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems like we are on the cusp of an explosion of creativity fed by all these advances.  A great time to be alive.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It is easy to be concerned about the nation and the world. So much bad news and misbehavior.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Hard Cash Valley, Lessons In Chemistry, History of the Bible, Rapid Skill Acquisition</title><link href="/blog/hard-cash-valley" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Hard Cash Valley, Lessons In Chemistry, History of the Bible, Rapid Skill Acquisition" /><published>2022-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/blog/hard-cash-valley</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/hard-cash-valley">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/45046684-hard-cash-valley&quot;&gt;Hard Cash Valley&lt;/a&gt; by Brian Panowich. A solid detective tale in rural northern Georgia (the state).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/57684325-lessons-in-chemistry&quot;&gt;Lessons In Chemistry&lt;/a&gt; by Bonnie Garmus.  The Julia Childs story on steroids.  The characters felt a little light at first but it evolved into a very touching story.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/44585804-a-history-of-the-bible&quot;&gt;A History of the Bible: The Story of the World’s Most Influential Book&lt;/a&gt; by John Barton.  This is quite a deep look, more than I wanted, and so I eventually set it down. But I still recommend it if you want to understand the development and structure of the bible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/44058556-the-science-of-rapid-skill-acquisition&quot;&gt;The Science of Rapid Skill Acquisition: Advanced Methods to Learn, Remember, and Master New Skills and Information&lt;/a&gt; by Peter Hollins.  This would have been a nice book to have at the beginning of my serious learning career back when I was 17 or 18.  Some good basic frameworks and I appreciate how he stresses teaching as just being on the learning spectrum, at one end.  I would not characterize anything in here as “science” or “advanced” though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hard Cash Valley by Brian Panowich. A solid detective tale in rural northern Georgia (the state). Lessons In Chemistry by Bonnie Garmus. The Julia Childs story on steroids. The characters felt a little light at first but it evolved into a very touching story. A History of the Bible: The Story of the World’s Most Influential Book by John Barton. This is quite a deep look, more than I wanted, and so I eventually set it down. But I still recommend it if you want to understand the development and structure of the bible. The Science of Rapid Skill Acquisition: Advanced Methods to Learn, Remember, and Master New Skills and Information by Peter Hollins. This would have been a nice book to have at the beginning of my serious learning career back when I was 17 or 18. Some good basic frameworks and I appreciate how he stresses teaching as just being on the learning spectrum, at one end. I would not characterize anything in here as “science” or “advanced” though.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – The Space Between Worlds, Blood and Daring, Civil Wars, Shantaram</title><link href="/blog/space-between-worlds" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – The Space Between Worlds, Blood and Daring, Civil Wars, Shantaram" /><published>2022-08-31T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-08-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/blog/space-between-worlds</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/space-between-worlds">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43301353-the-space-between-worlds&quot;&gt;The Space Between Worlds&lt;/a&gt; by Micaiah Johnson. Good story of parallel universes. A traveller betweens worlds deal with conspiracies and politics across multiple similar worlds with similar characters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/19192410-blood-and-daring&quot;&gt;Blood and Daring: How Canada Fought the American Civil War and Forged a Nation&lt;/a&gt; by John Boyko.  I know pathetically little about Canadian history, this was interesting and easy to get into as it related to history I already knew well, the American Civil War.  I did not realize the impact the Civil War had across the border.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/58133497-how-civil-wars-start&quot;&gt;How Civil Wars Start&lt;/a&gt; by Barbara F. Walter.  Very good data on history of civil wars, and pinpointing the common factor – loss of power by a historically controlling group. When it got to remedies, the book was a little less on target – a lot of theoretically good but impractical ideas, and too many of them.  We are only going to be able to pull a few levers, I am not sure this book helped me understand which.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/9413297-shantaram&quot;&gt;Shantaram&lt;/a&gt; by Gregory David Roberts.  Wow, this is a long book, but that is because it has so much story packed into it.  War, organized crime, prison, prison escapes, murder, betrayal, love, humour, this has it all.  Not sure why I waited so long to read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Space Between Worlds by Micaiah Johnson. Good story of parallel universes. A traveller betweens worlds deal with conspiracies and politics across multiple similar worlds with similar characters. Blood and Daring: How Canada Fought the American Civil War and Forged a Nation by John Boyko. I know pathetically little about Canadian history, this was interesting and easy to get into as it related to history I already knew well, the American Civil War. I did not realize the impact the Civil War had across the border. How Civil Wars Start by Barbara F. Walter. Very good data on history of civil wars, and pinpointing the common factor – loss of power by a historically controlling group. When it got to remedies, the book was a little less on target – a lot of theoretically good but impractical ideas, and too many of them. We are only going to be able to pull a few levers, I am not sure this book helped me understand which. Shantaram by Gregory David Roberts. Wow, this is a long book, but that is because it has so much story packed into it. War, organized crime, prison, prison escapes, murder, betrayal, love, humour, this has it all. Not sure why I waited so long to read.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What shall we choose next?</title><link href="/blog/we-choose-to-go-to-the-moon" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What shall we choose next?" /><published>2022-08-21T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-08-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/blog/we-choose-to-go-to-the-moon</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/we-choose-to-go-to-the-moon">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been reflecting on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/We_choose_to_go_to_the_Moon&quot;&gt;JFK’s “We choose to go to the Moon” speech&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote style=&quot;padding-left:200px;padding-right:200px;font-size:medium&quot;&gt;
We choose to go to the Moon in this decade and do the other things, not because they are easy, but because they are hard; because that goal will serve to organize and measure the best of our energies and skills, because that challenge is one that we are willing to accept, one we are unwilling to postpone, and one we intend to win... -- &lt;i&gt;John F. Kennedy&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most interesting part is how this will bring out the best of our energies and skills.  An aspirational goal can really pull people together – the challenge displaces the petty everyday tussles we stumble into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To achieve the moon goal, the US government made significant investments in science and technology.  DARPA was founded in 1958, motivated by Sputnik, and was instrumental in the race to the moon, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DARPA&quot;&gt;has continued to generate incredible impact&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote style=&quot;padding-left:200px;padding-right:200px;font-size:medium&quot;&gt;
The Economist has called DARPA the agency &quot;that shaped the modern world,&quot; and pointed out that &quot;Moderna’s covid-19 vaccine sits alongside weather satellites, GPS, drones, stealth technology, voice interfaces, the personal computer and the internet on the list of innovations for which DARPA can claim at least partial credit.&quot; Its track record of success has inspired governments around the world to launch similar research and development agencies.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Viewed as a venture investor, DARPA and other government investments &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.profgalloway.com/welfare-queens/&quot;&gt;have been the best investments we’ve ever made&lt;/a&gt;, far outpacing the impact of private venture capital:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote style=&quot;padding-left:200px;padding-right:200px;font-size:medium&quot;&gt;
One investor funded the computer, the internet, speech recognition, last-mile distribution, mapping the human genome, the core technologies of fracking, and the first horizontal shale drill, and today it’s driving down the cost of solar and wind power below that of coal. -- &lt;i&gt;Scott Galloway&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now face new sputnik-like challenges – innovation that is critical to future economic development, but where the US is failing to keep pace with other nations, now China. Consider &lt;a href=&quot;https://noahpinion.substack.com/p/the-war-economy-is-america-falling&quot;&gt;our (potential) science gap with China&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote style=&quot;padding-left:200px;padding-right:200px;font-size:medium&quot;&gt;
Well, the point should be obvious now. When China has quantum computers a million times faster than Google’s, satellites that can talk securely with the Earth via quantum entanglement, quantum magnetometers that can (possibly) find our most secret submarines, and autonomous drone swarms that can fly through dense forests, Congress would have to be insane to worry about pinching a few pennies. -- &lt;i&gt;Noah Smith&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responding to this challenge will generate new industries and new jobs for our children, just as DARPA did.  Failing to respond will result in high value industries shifting to other nations, dragging down the ability of US citizens to enjoy a high standard of living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am glad to see the US has recently passed laws supporting semiconductor investment and renewables investment.  Those are probably key industries going forward. But we haven’t articulated a moonshot goal.  And we need one to help us all rise above the daily squabbles and focus on a positive future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not sure what the right moonshot goal is, but it is not the Inflation Reduction Act – too prosaic, doesn’t lift us up.  And it is not a Green New Deal – too abstract, too diffuse.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’ve been reflecting on JFK’s “We choose to go to the Moon” speech:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Fooled by the Winners, Polarized, Vanishing Asia, Broken Glass, Will to Kill</title><link href="/blog/fooled" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Fooled by the Winners, Polarized, Vanishing Asia, Broken Glass, Will to Kill" /><published>2022-08-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-08-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/blog/fooled</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/fooled">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/58919327-fooled-by-the-winners&quot;&gt;Fooled by the Winners&lt;/a&gt; by David Lockwood.  The parts of this book that went into survivor bias were decent, but marred by the midbook tangent off into climate change and our potential responses to it.  I don’t necessarily disagree with much (but not all) of the author’s view on climate change, but it just derailed the whole book, and the pages could have been better spent digging into survivor bias examples and implications.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/52098718-why-we-re-polarized&quot;&gt;Why We’re Polarized&lt;/a&gt; by Ezra Klein. Good assessment of the state and causes of polarization. Highest recommendation, I learned a lot.  One insight about our changing demographics for instance – political power shifts lag 10 years behind demographic shifts, while cultural shifts lead by 10 years.  This alone creates a lot of stress in our society.  Also interesting is how the parties both basically abdicated control of candidate selection to the popular vote, and the implications of that change.  A ton of good stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60433342-vanishing-asia&quot;&gt;Vanishing Asia&lt;/a&gt; by Kevin Kelly.  Photos of an incredible broad swath of human society.  Entrancing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/52282065-broken-glass&quot;&gt;Broken Glass: Mies Van Der Rohe, Edith Farnsworth, and the Fight Over a Modernist Masterpiece&lt;/a&gt; by Alex Beam. An architecture project gone awry, triumph of ego and design over utility.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/54983580-a-will-to-kill&quot;&gt;A Will to Kill&lt;/a&gt; by R.V. Raman.  Clumsily authored, and really clumsily formatted for the Kimdle, very hard to read, obviously automatically converted into Kindle format with very little care – choppy paragraph breaks, missing quotation marks around speech, just painful to look at.  Ugh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Fooled by the Winners by David Lockwood. The parts of this book that went into survivor bias were decent, but marred by the midbook tangent off into climate change and our potential responses to it. I don’t necessarily disagree with much (but not all) of the author’s view on climate change, but it just derailed the whole book, and the pages could have been better spent digging into survivor bias examples and implications. Why We’re Polarized by Ezra Klein. Good assessment of the state and causes of polarization. Highest recommendation, I learned a lot. One insight about our changing demographics for instance – political power shifts lag 10 years behind demographic shifts, while cultural shifts lead by 10 years. This alone creates a lot of stress in our society. Also interesting is how the parties both basically abdicated control of candidate selection to the popular vote, and the implications of that change. A ton of good stuff. Vanishing Asia by Kevin Kelly. Photos of an incredible broad swath of human society. Entrancing. Broken Glass: Mies Van Der Rohe, Edith Farnsworth, and the Fight Over a Modernist Masterpiece by Alex Beam. An architecture project gone awry, triumph of ego and design over utility. A Will to Kill by R.V. Raman. Clumsily authored, and really clumsily formatted for the Kimdle, very hard to read, obviously automatically converted into Kindle format with very little care – choppy paragraph breaks, missing quotation marks around speech, just painful to look at. Ugh.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – How Lucky, City of Orange, Dream and the Tomb, Falling, Addie LaRue</title><link href="/blog/how-lucky" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – How Lucky, City of Orange, Dream and the Tomb, Falling, Addie LaRue" /><published>2022-07-21T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-07-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/blog/how-lucky</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/how-lucky">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/54870216-how-lucky&quot;&gt;How Lucky&lt;/a&gt; by Will Leitch.  A moderately entertaining detective tale with a twist, the main character is beset by a crippling disease (spinal muscular atrophy) and is fighting to make something of their own life.  An easy read.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/57699025-city-of-orange&quot;&gt;City of Orange&lt;/a&gt; by David Yoon.  Seemed like the kind of post-apocalyptic tale I would like, but could never connect with the character or the situation.  The last(?) man alive fighting for existence on a deserted earth.  I gave up before I could find out what happened.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/44794235-the-dream-and-the-tomb&quot;&gt;The Dream and The Tomb&lt;/a&gt; by Robert Payne.  A history of the Crusades, largely from the European side.  What a morass of ego and ill-planning and wishful thinking.  Good lessons for any nation considering an overseas misadventure.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/56614951-falling&quot;&gt;Falling&lt;/a&gt; by T.J. Newman.  Formulaic and unexciting from the start.  Gave up fast.  Inspired me to remove a bunch of other crappy books from my library, so that is good.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/50623864-the-invisible-life-of-addie-larue&quot;&gt;The Invisible Life of Addie LaRue&lt;/a&gt; by V.E. Schwab.  A young woman makes a deal with the devil and then spends centuries fighting against the deal.  Started out slowly but built nicely and couldn’t put it down by the end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">How Lucky by Will Leitch. A moderately entertaining detective tale with a twist, the main character is beset by a crippling disease (spinal muscular atrophy) and is fighting to make something of their own life. An easy read. City of Orange by David Yoon. Seemed like the kind of post-apocalyptic tale I would like, but could never connect with the character or the situation. The last(?) man alive fighting for existence on a deserted earth. I gave up before I could find out what happened. The Dream and The Tomb by Robert Payne. A history of the Crusades, largely from the European side. What a morass of ego and ill-planning and wishful thinking. Good lessons for any nation considering an overseas misadventure. Falling by T.J. Newman. Formulaic and unexciting from the start. Gave up fast. Inspired me to remove a bunch of other crappy books from my library, so that is good. The Invisible Life of Addie LaRue by V.E. Schwab. A young woman makes a deal with the devil and then spends centuries fighting against the deal. Started out slowly but built nicely and couldn’t put it down by the end.</summary></entry></feed>