<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-02-11T11:26:47-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">A Little Ludwig Goes a Long Way</title><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – The Mountain In The Sea, Breakheart Pass, Nophek Gloss, Bad Mexicans</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/books" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – The Mountain In The Sea, Breakheart Pass, Nophek Gloss, Bad Mexicans" /><published>2023-02-11T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-02-11T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/books</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/books">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/59808603-the-mountain-in-the-sea&quot;&gt;The Mountain In The Sea&lt;/a&gt; by Ray Nayler.  Good introspective tale about discovery and creation of different kinds of intelligences. Octopi are fascinating.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/149607.Breakheart_Pass&quot;&gt;Breakheart Pass&lt;/a&gt; by Alistair MacLean.  As a kid I read all MacLean’s books and loved them.  As a lark I reread one.  OK it is overwritten, under-edited, a little trite – but there is a great story in the bones of this book, I understand why I ate them up.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/54539799-nophek-gloss&quot;&gt;Nophek Gloss&lt;/a&gt; by Essa Hansen.  I am not sure why I gave this book so much of a chance, it is a fairly typical hero saga with really dumb sci fi elements.  Not worth it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/61055606-bad-mexicans&quot;&gt;Bad Mexicans&lt;/a&gt; by Kelly Lytle Hernandez.  Chock full of history that I never learned, and I really should know, but the book is just boring.  Kept falling asleep.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Mountain In The Sea by Ray Nayler. Good introspective tale about discovery and creation of different kinds of intelligences. Octopi are fascinating. Breakheart Pass by Alistair MacLean. As a kid I read all MacLean’s books and loved them. As a lark I reread one. OK it is overwritten, under-edited, a little trite – but there is a great story in the bones of this book, I understand why I ate them up. Nophek Gloss by Essa Hansen. I am not sure why I gave this book so much of a chance, it is a fairly typical hero saga with really dumb sci fi elements. Not worth it. Bad Mexicans by Kelly Lytle Hernandez. Chock full of history that I never learned, and I really should know, but the book is just boring. Kept falling asleep.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Trust, The Future is History, China RX</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/trust" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Trust, The Future is History, China RX" /><published>2023-01-15T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-15T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/trust</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/trust">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/59039413-trust&quot;&gt;Trust&lt;/a&gt; by Hernan Diaz.  Worthy of all the accolades.  The truth is slowly unravelled as different characters relate their experience, stripping away facade after facade.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/35112020-the-future-is-history&quot;&gt;The Future Is History: How Totalitarianism Reclaimed Russia&lt;/a&gt; by Masha Gessen.  The story of the end of the Soviet Union and the rise of the current Russian goverment/society told thru the stories of people who endured it.  Very sobering assessment of Russian society and government, the enthusiasm for and commitment to totalitarianism runs deep.  Even more a supporter of a free Ukraine after reading this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/37492588-china-rx&quot;&gt;China Rx: Exposing the Risks of America’s Dependence on China for Medicine&lt;/a&gt; by Rosemary Gibson.  A little histrionic at times, and overly long and repetitive, but raises good issues.  There is a glaring hole in the recommendations, there is no way we can depend on inspections of manufacturing facilities in the US or overseas to ensure quality, we have to perform random sample testing of product in the field and take fast action based on problems identified.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Trust by Hernan Diaz. Worthy of all the accolades. The truth is slowly unravelled as different characters relate their experience, stripping away facade after facade. The Future Is History: How Totalitarianism Reclaimed Russia by Masha Gessen. The story of the end of the Soviet Union and the rise of the current Russian goverment/society told thru the stories of people who endured it. Very sobering assessment of Russian society and government, the enthusiasm for and commitment to totalitarianism runs deep. Even more a supporter of a free Ukraine after reading this. China Rx: Exposing the Risks of America’s Dependence on China for Medicine by Rosemary Gibson. A little histrionic at times, and overly long and repetitive, but raises good issues. There is a glaring hole in the recommendations, there is no way we can depend on inspections of manufacturing facilities in the US or overseas to ensure quality, we have to perform random sample testing of product in the field and take fast action based on problems identified.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I’m off twitter for now</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/bye-bye-twitter" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I’m off twitter for now" /><published>2022-12-18T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-18T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/bye-bye-twitter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/bye-bye-twitter">&lt;p&gt;Elon has every right to have whatever editorial policy he wants and to support whatever membership he wants.  It is his company.  And Twitter is not some special place, some sacred commons — it is just another media site, and like every media site, it is going to have a slant and a certain audience goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increasingly, the site doesn’t match with my interests.  It is becoming an outrage fest and Elon is encouraging that.  Elon posts provocative stuff, people express outrage, and other people express outrage about the outrage.  Elon isn’t the only driver of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is we are awash in tools to express ourselves, it has never been easier to get your voice out and connect with people.  I read and post on Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, Linkedin, Mastodon, Post, Goodreads, Discord, Wordpress, Github, and more.  I’ve considered and discarded so many alternatives, I can’t remember them all.  Social networks, microblogging platforms, short message platforms, video clip sharing services, photo sharing services, blogging tools, newsletter tools, website hosting, discussion forums, video hosting services — there are so many tools available and more every day.  I can’t keep up with them all, I have probably missed entire categories of tools.  And in every category there are multiple choices, with multiple different content policies.  There is a place for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter and its adherents don’t owe me anything and I don’t owe twitter or anyone on it a listen.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Elon has every right to have whatever editorial policy he wants and to support whatever membership he wants. It is his company. And Twitter is not some special place, some sacred commons — it is just another media site, and like every media site, it is going to have a slant and a certain audience goal.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Sea of Tranquility, The Year of Peril, Overstory, Boys and Men, Sandworm, Fortune Favors the Dead</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/tranquility" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Sea of Tranquility, The Year of Peril, Overstory, Boys and Men, Sandworm, Fortune Favors the Dead" /><published>2022-12-17T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/tranquility</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/tranquility">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/58446227-sea-of-tranquility&quot;&gt;Sea of Tranquility&lt;/a&gt; by Emily St. John Mandel.  What if our world really is just a simulation?  An OK tale but not a knockout.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/53499001-the-year-of-peril&quot;&gt;The Year of Peril: America in 1942&lt;/a&gt; by Tracy Campbell.  Interesting look at the stresses in American society in 1942.  We look back now and feel like our victory in WWII was inevitable and that all Americans pulled together.  Reality is much messier.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40180098-the-overstory&quot;&gt;The Overstory&lt;/a&gt; by Richard Powers.  I don’t get it.  Plodding.  Couldn’t be bothered to finish it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60613920-of-boys-and-men&quot;&gt;Of Boys and Men: Why the Modern Male Is Struggling, Why It Matters, and What to Do about It&lt;/a&gt; by Richard B. Reeves.  Very thought provoking.  This is not some apologist text about men, it is a very critical view of how we are raised and molded and demands that we do better.  It is also very critical of Democratic Party approaches to the issue.  The solutions are a little too straight line but worth reading.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41436213-sandworm&quot;&gt;Sandworm: A New Era of Cyberwar and the Hunt for the Kremlin’s Most Dangerous Hackers&lt;/a&gt; by Andy Greenberg.  I don’t know, just didn’t really grab me.  Something about the narrative was just kind of boring.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/50666983-fortune-favors-the-dead&quot;&gt;Fortune Favors the Dead&lt;/a&gt; by Stephen Spotswood.  Oh what a great detective story, two wonderful main characters in the Holmes/Watson tradition, vulnerable and very human.  Really liked it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Sea of Tranquility by Emily St. John Mandel. What if our world really is just a simulation? An OK tale but not a knockout. The Year of Peril: America in 1942 by Tracy Campbell. Interesting look at the stresses in American society in 1942. We look back now and feel like our victory in WWII was inevitable and that all Americans pulled together. Reality is much messier. The Overstory by Richard Powers. I don’t get it. Plodding. Couldn’t be bothered to finish it. Of Boys and Men: Why the Modern Male Is Struggling, Why It Matters, and What to Do about It by Richard B. Reeves. Very thought provoking. This is not some apologist text about men, it is a very critical view of how we are raised and molded and demands that we do better. It is also very critical of Democratic Party approaches to the issue. The solutions are a little too straight line but worth reading. Sandworm: A New Era of Cyberwar and the Hunt for the Kremlin’s Most Dangerous Hackers by Andy Greenberg. I don’t know, just didn’t really grab me. Something about the narrative was just kind of boring. Fortune Favors the Dead by Stephen Spotswood. Oh what a great detective story, two wonderful main characters in the Holmes/Watson tradition, vulnerable and very human. Really liked it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Top 6 Books</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/top-five" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Top 6 Books" /><published>2022-11-25T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-11-25T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/top-five</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/top-five">&lt;p&gt;Bill Gates recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatesnotes.com/About-Bill-Gates/Holiday-Books-2022&quot;&gt;posted some of his favorite books&lt;/a&gt;.  And it has inspired me to think about my all time favorites.  I have 1200+ books listed on Goodreads and I am sure there are another 500-1000 I’ve read that I have never put on Goodreads (for instance, I read every Allen Drury political drama back in my teens, loved them, but I’ve never bothered to put on Goodreads).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I narrowed my list down to 6 with some alternates as well.  (Sorry I couldn’t get to 5, Bill is better at this than I am)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/378.The_Phantom_Tollbooth&quot;&gt;The Phantom Tollbooth&lt;/a&gt; by Norton Juster with illustrations by Jules Feiffer.  This book hooked me on reading as a young reader, I loved the story and the wordplay.  It is probably not a great adult book read but I think it is fabulous for young readers.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17157681-the-hobbit-part-one&quot;&gt;The Hobbit&lt;/a&gt; is of course a great choice as well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/112537.Rendezvous_with_Rama&quot;&gt;Rendezvous with Rama&lt;/a&gt; by Arthur C. Clarke.  I read a ton of classic science fiction and I loved much of it.  Rama really had a sense of mystery and wonder that I enjoyed.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/234225.Dune&quot;&gt;Dune&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/77566.Hyperion&quot;&gt;Hyperion&lt;/a&gt; are great books in the genre as well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18423.The_Left_Hand_of_Darkness&quot;&gt;The Left Hand of Darkness&lt;/a&gt; by Ursula K. Leguin.  I love all of Leguin’s works, this book showed me that speculative fiction could be so much deeper.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/334176.The_Sparrow&quot;&gt;The Sparrow&lt;/a&gt; is an excellent choice too.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1138543.The_Strange_Death_of_Liberal_England&quot;&gt;The Strange Death of Liberal England&lt;/a&gt; by George Dangerfield.  One of my favorite history books about a period of great change, just so well written. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1128055.Hitler_s_Thirty_Days_to_Power&quot;&gt;Hitler’s Thirty Days to Power&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/50159458-kent-state&quot;&gt;Kent State: Four Dead in Ohio&lt;/a&gt; are excellent choices as well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/262304.The_Wild_Party&quot;&gt;The Wild Party&lt;/a&gt; by Joseph Moncure March with illustrations by Art Spiegelman.  A quirky little piece of fiction that I find incredibly entertaining.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11149.The_Screwtape_Letters&quot;&gt;The Screwtape Letters&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/19288259-dear-committee-members&quot;&gt;Dear Committee Members&lt;/a&gt; are fun choices too.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/54218.The_Mismeasure_of_Man&quot;&gt;The Mismeasure of Man&lt;/a&gt; by Stephen Jay Gould.  All of Gould’s work is excellent, this set of analyses is well argued and well written.  Other good non-fiction choices are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13629.The_Mythical_Man_Month&quot;&gt;The Mythical Man-Month&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/35187180-the-death-and-life-of-the-great-lakes&quot;&gt;The Death and Life of the Great Lakes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11721966-good-strategy-bad-strategy&quot;&gt;Good Strategy, Bad Strategy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/242472.The_Black_Swan&quot;&gt;The Black Swan&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17884043-tune-in&quot;&gt;Tune In&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Bill Gates recently posted some of his favorite books. And it has inspired me to think about my all time favorites. I have 1200+ books listed on Goodreads and I am sure there are another 500-1000 I’ve read that I have never put on Goodreads (for instance, I read every Allen Drury political drama back in my teens, loved them, but I’ve never bothered to put on Goodreads).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Knight Series, Pyramid of Lies, Spin, The Secret History</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/knight" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Knight Series, Pyramid of Lies, Spin, The Secret History" /><published>2022-11-18T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-11-18T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/knight</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/knight">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/56985443-her-name-is-knight&quot;&gt;Her Name Is Knight&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/59132250-they-come-at-knight&quot;&gt;They Come At Knight&lt;/a&gt; by Yasmin Angoe.  The first book is a good start to a thriller series featuring a young African assassin who has been thru a hellacious early life, and is now starting to avenge herself.  The tale continues int he second book, which loses its way for a little while, although ends well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/61640141-the-pyramid-of-lies&quot;&gt;The Pyramid of Lies: Lex Greensill and the Billion-Dollar Scandal&lt;/a&gt; by Duncan Mavin.  More detail than I really wanted on this scandal.  I am excited to read the equivalent about Sam Bankman-Fried some day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/59028343-spin&quot;&gt;Spin&lt;/a&gt; by Robert Charles Wilson.  Great tale of three close friends who deal with the transformation of Earth by alien technologies.  Great characters dealing with stress.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29044.The_Secret_History&quot;&gt;The Secret History&lt;/a&gt; by Donna Tartt.  This book seems well written, but the characters are unpleasant and the situation is unpleasant and I just didn’t enjoy putting this into my head.  Moving on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Her Name Is Knight, They Come At Knight by Yasmin Angoe. The first book is a good start to a thriller series featuring a young African assassin who has been thru a hellacious early life, and is now starting to avenge herself. The tale continues int he second book, which loses its way for a little while, although ends well. The Pyramid of Lies: Lex Greensill and the Billion-Dollar Scandal by Duncan Mavin. More detail than I really wanted on this scandal. I am excited to read the equivalent about Sam Bankman-Fried some day. Spin by Robert Charles Wilson. Great tale of three close friends who deal with the transformation of Earth by alien technologies. Great characters dealing with stress. The Secret History by Donna Tartt. This book seems well written, but the characters are unpleasant and the situation is unpleasant and I just didn’t enjoy putting this into my head. Moving on.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – American and Iran, Toaster Project, Foundryside, Freezing Order, Nazi Billionaires</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/american-and-iran" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – American and Iran, Toaster Project, Foundryside, Freezing Order, Nazi Billionaires" /><published>2022-10-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/american-and-iran</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/american-and-iran">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/49201929-america-and-iran&quot;&gt;America and Iran: A History 1720 to the Present&lt;/a&gt; by John Ghazvinian.  This has been a long read, and an exceptional read.  So much I didn’t know.  Heartbreaking, so much ill will and bad behaviour between the countries, serving no one’s purpose.  Such opportunity lost.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18904629-the-toaster-project&quot;&gt;The Toaster Project: Or A Heroic Attempt to Build a Simple Electric Appliance from Scratch&lt;/a&gt; by Thomas Thwaites.  A very short book documenting this project. Reminds you of just how advanced and specialized and interconnected our society is; the days of living along off the land are long gone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/37173847-foundryside&quot;&gt;Foundryside&lt;/a&gt; by Robert Jackson Bennett.  Quite entertaining fantasy romp.  A young thief gains access to magical secrets and upends the power structure of a country.  Good characters.  First of a series and I’m sure I’d enjoy the rest, tho this works very well on its own.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60399061-freezing-order&quot;&gt;Freezing Order: A True Story of Money Laundering, Murder, and Surviving Vladimir Putin’s Wrath&lt;/a&gt; by Bill Browder.  A pretty exciting tale about money laundering and the attempts to fight it over the last 2 decades.  A very dangerous fight.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60842883-nazi-billionaires&quot;&gt;Nazi Billionaires: The Dark History of Germany’s Wealthiest Dynasties&lt;/a&gt; by David de Jong.  A long retelling of the wealth of some of Germany’s richest people, and how many of these families benefitted from Nazi ties.  The book kind of loses its way in the flood of never ending details and maybe that is the point – the ties to the Nazis were pervasive, and never really resolved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">America and Iran: A History 1720 to the Present by John Ghazvinian. This has been a long read, and an exceptional read. So much I didn’t know. Heartbreaking, so much ill will and bad behaviour between the countries, serving no one’s purpose. Such opportunity lost. The Toaster Project: Or A Heroic Attempt to Build a Simple Electric Appliance from Scratch by Thomas Thwaites. A very short book documenting this project. Reminds you of just how advanced and specialized and interconnected our society is; the days of living along off the land are long gone. Foundryside by Robert Jackson Bennett. Quite entertaining fantasy romp. A young thief gains access to magical secrets and upends the power structure of a country. Good characters. First of a series and I’m sure I’d enjoy the rest, tho this works very well on its own. Freezing Order: A True Story of Money Laundering, Murder, and Surviving Vladimir Putin’s Wrath by Bill Browder. A pretty exciting tale about money laundering and the attempts to fight it over the last 2 decades. A very dangerous fight. Nazi Billionaires: The Dark History of Germany’s Wealthiest Dynasties by David de Jong. A long retelling of the wealth of some of Germany’s richest people, and how many of these families benefitted from Nazi ties. The book kind of loses its way in the flood of never ending details and maybe that is the point – the ties to the Nazis were pervasive, and never really resolved.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">3 features I’d like in streaming media</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/streaming" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="3 features I’d like in streaming media" /><published>2022-10-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/streaming</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/streaming">&lt;p&gt;1, I really wish the AppleTV device had features for serious sports viewers.  PIP so I can keep up with multiple games.  Fast 1-button switching between two or three different games.  I used to have these features on my old cable boxes, we have really lost something.  And sports enthusiasts would pay for these features, if there was a special sports version of the appletv box I would buy it in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2, I’d love to see my viewing history for any service as I can with Netflix (although even on Netflix, it is buried in a stupid place in the UX).  I’d like to be able to quickly rate shows, filter my history, share it or a filtered subset of it, etc.  Every week my kids ask me “what did you watch good this week?” and I have to scramble to answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3, I wish all streaming services would integrate with either/both AppleTV and Amazon aggregation features - easy account activation/deactivation, viewing within the app, participation in favorites list, etc.  I want to use an aggregator and I don’t care which one particularly.  I don’t want to have 17 logins with 17 different apps with 17 different UXes – and boy are the UXes on some of the lesser streaming services bad, Showtime I’m looking at you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">1, I really wish the AppleTV device had features for serious sports viewers. PIP so I can keep up with multiple games. Fast 1-button switching between two or three different games. I used to have these features on my old cable boxes, we have really lost something. And sports enthusiasts would pay for these features, if there was a special sports version of the appletv box I would buy it in seconds.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Optimism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/optimism" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Optimism" /><published>2022-10-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/optimism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/optimism">&lt;p&gt;It is easy to be concerned about the nation and the world.  So much bad news and misbehavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wow, do I feel optimistic this week.  Like so many people I’ve been playing around with &lt;a href=&quot;https://stability.ai&quot;&gt;Stable Diffusion&lt;/a&gt;, and to a lesser extent Midjourney and Dall-E 2. Tons of fun, the open nature of Stable Diffusion makes it easy to play with, I’m reminded of how much fun it was the first time I got a PC.  And the rate of innovation around it is incredible – a &lt;a href=&quot;https://keras.io/guides/keras_cv/generate_images_with_stable_diffusion/&quot;&gt;KerasCV port&lt;/a&gt; which seems super fast, alternative web UIs like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AUTOMATIC1111/stable-diffusion-webui&quot;&gt;Automatic1111&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/deforum/stable-diffusion&quot;&gt;animation&lt;/a&gt; aupport, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nateraw/stable-diffusion-videos&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; applications, tools to do incremental training for new objects and styles, prompt generation tools, landscape generation tools, inpainting, outpainting, masking, mosaicing, audio equivalents – it is hard to keep up with everything.  Incredibly exciting time, great energy.  Lots of issues around copyright and IP protection to be figured out, but still super exciting.  I like &lt;a href=&quot;https://lspace.swyx.io/p/multiverse-not-metaverse&quot;&gt;this phrasing&lt;/a&gt; – the creative multiverse is way more exciting than some corporate metaverse.  Stable Diffusion and its kin are going to be major accelerants for every creative task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I see reasons for great optimism outside software.  I am relatively stupid about things biologic, but I get pretty excited when I read articles like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tsungxu.com/performance-biomaterials&quot;&gt;Biomanufactured Materials Are Coming&lt;/a&gt;.  Imagine if we can create Moore’s Law equivalents for biologic materials – ever cheaper, ever higher volume, ever more function biologics – the applications are pretty endless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then look at the space industry – &lt;a href=&quot;https://brycetech.com/reports/report-documents/Bryce_Briefing_2022_Q2.pdf&quot;&gt;Launch volumes are going way up, costs are going way down&lt;/a&gt;.  And there are a ton of companies working hard to make this happen faster – for instance &lt;a href=&quot;stokespace.com&quot;&gt;Stoke Space&lt;/a&gt;.  Getting the free market to work on this challenge has been brilliant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could probably get just as excited about the declining cost of renewable energy and the implications of much cheaper energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems like we are on the cusp of an explosion of creativity fed by all these advances.  A great time to be alive.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It is easy to be concerned about the nation and the world. So much bad news and misbehavior.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Hard Cash Valley, Lessons In Chemistry, History of the Bible, Rapid Skill Acquisition</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/hard-cash-valley" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Hard Cash Valley, Lessons In Chemistry, History of the Bible, Rapid Skill Acquisition" /><published>2022-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/hard-cash-valley</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/hard-cash-valley">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/45046684-hard-cash-valley&quot;&gt;Hard Cash Valley&lt;/a&gt; by Brian Panowich. A solid detective tale in rural northern Georgia (the state).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/57684325-lessons-in-chemistry&quot;&gt;Lessons In Chemistry&lt;/a&gt; by Bonnie Garmus.  The Julia Childs story on steroids.  The characters felt a little light at first but it evolved into a very touching story.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/44585804-a-history-of-the-bible&quot;&gt;A History of the Bible: The Story of the World’s Most Influential Book&lt;/a&gt; by John Barton.  This is quite a deep look, more than I wanted, and so I eventually set it down. But I still recommend it if you want to understand the development and structure of the bible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/44058556-the-science-of-rapid-skill-acquisition&quot;&gt;The Science of Rapid Skill Acquisition: Advanced Methods to Learn, Remember, and Master New Skills and Information&lt;/a&gt; by Peter Hollins.  This would have been a nice book to have at the beginning of my serious learning career back when I was 17 or 18.  Some good basic frameworks and I appreciate how he stresses teaching as just being on the learning spectrum, at one end.  I would not characterize anything in here as “science” or “advanced” though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hard Cash Valley by Brian Panowich. A solid detective tale in rural northern Georgia (the state). Lessons In Chemistry by Bonnie Garmus. The Julia Childs story on steroids. The characters felt a little light at first but it evolved into a very touching story. A History of the Bible: The Story of the World’s Most Influential Book by John Barton. This is quite a deep look, more than I wanted, and so I eventually set it down. But I still recommend it if you want to understand the development and structure of the bible. The Science of Rapid Skill Acquisition: Advanced Methods to Learn, Remember, and Master New Skills and Information by Peter Hollins. This would have been a nice book to have at the beginning of my serious learning career back when I was 17 or 18. Some good basic frameworks and I appreciate how he stresses teaching as just being on the learning spectrum, at one end. I would not characterize anything in here as “science” or “advanced” though.</summary></entry></feed>