<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-06-12T17:09:59-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">A Little Ludwig Goes a Long Way</title><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Pixel, This Tender Land, Karachi Vice, Land of Big Numbers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/pixel" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Pixel, This Tender Land, Karachi Vice, Land of Big Numbers" /><published>2022-06-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-06-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/pixel</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/pixel">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/55643209-a-biography-of-the-pixel&quot;&gt;A Biography of the Pixel&lt;/a&gt; by Alvy Ray Smith.  Expansive and deep exploration of the evolution of digital media and its fundamental element.  Great depth and insight.  A little overwhelming in depth at times.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25813942-this-tender-land&quot;&gt;This Tender Land&lt;/a&gt; by William Kent Krueger.  Great mashup of the Odyssey and Huck Finn.  Great characters, very enjoyable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/55779097-karachi-vice&quot;&gt;Karachi Vice&lt;/a&gt; by Samira Shackle.  True tales of life on the streets of Karachi.  Tough lives.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/45154216-land-of-big-numbers&quot;&gt;Land of Big Numbers&lt;/a&gt; by Te-Ping Chen.  Not usually a short story fan but this was fascinating. The combination of unrestrained market development and intrusive authoritarian presence is a strange mix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A Biography of the Pixel by Alvy Ray Smith. Expansive and deep exploration of the evolution of digital media and its fundamental element. Great depth and insight. A little overwhelming in depth at times. This Tender Land by William Kent Krueger. Great mashup of the Odyssey and Huck Finn. Great characters, very enjoyable. Karachi Vice by Samira Shackle. True tales of life on the streets of Karachi. Tough lives. Land of Big Numbers by Te-Ping Chen. Not usually a short story fan but this was fascinating. The combination of unrestrained market development and intrusive authoritarian presence is a strange mix.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Exit Strategy, Build</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/exit-strategy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Exit Strategy, Build" /><published>2022-05-19T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-05-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/exit-strategy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/exit-strategy">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36687477-exit-strategy&quot;&gt;Exit Strategy&lt;/a&gt; by Charlton Pettus.  Solid thriller, one innovative use of DNA encoding, tho rest of book dragged at times.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/59696349-build&quot;&gt;Build&lt;/a&gt; by Tony Fadell.  Really really nice gift of advice about building products and companies.  Hat tip to @tfadell, a great leader and sharer.  Quite a contrast to some other tech luminaries who are pushing neolibertarian slop and crypto/web3 fraud, @tfadell is sharing great leadership and innovation guidance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Exit Strategy by Charlton Pettus. Solid thriller, one innovative use of DNA encoding, tho rest of book dragged at times. Build by Tony Fadell. Really really nice gift of advice about building products and companies. Hat tip to @tfadell, a great leader and sharer. Quite a contrast to some other tech luminaries who are pushing neolibertarian slop and crypto/web3 fraud, @tfadell is sharing great leadership and innovation guidance.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Whither Twitter, Buyer’s Guide, and other random stuff</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/twitter-buyer" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Whither Twitter, Buyer’s Guide, and other random stuff" /><published>2022-05-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-05-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/twitter-buyer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/twitter-buyer">&lt;p&gt;Well it has been a while since I have posted any observations.  I have improved my pickleball game tho.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;twitter&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several years ago, I reconsidered my use of Facebook, and made the decision to largely exit Facebook, and I haven’t really regretted it.  I’ve been doing the same recently for Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do get value out of Twitter.  College football smack talk and news, a little bit of community news, some technology info, the occasional news about friends.  But there is a lot of noise on Twitter, a lot of snark, a lot of “performative nonsense”, and maybe it is getting worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What should I expect out of Twitter?  Twitter is not some mystical thing.  It’s not our global conciousness, not our townsquare, not some magic public good.  It’s just a company trying to turn a buck by attracting eyeballs.  Viewing it as some special thing just leads to disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter has every right to publish/promote whatever content using whatever criteria it wants.  The choice may attract or drive away some users, may attract advertisers or not, may have other business implications.  Whatever, that is the Twitter’s first amendment right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter also doesn’t owe me or anyone a bullhorn.  It may or may not let me say what I want to say, Twitter may or may not amplify it.  That is Twitter’s right.   And I have the right to use or not use Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any new owner of Twitter will have the right to publish and promote whatever content they want, using whatever criteria they want.   It may be different than what the former owners did.  It may have different appeal to different users, advertisers, partners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I don’t like any of that, I can walk away at anytime.  No one is forcing me to use Twitter.  I can live without it — most of my family doesn’t regularly use Twitter, most of them don’t even have accounts.   Twitter doesn’t have particularly significant impacts on my work performance or on my relationships.  If and when it loses the entertainment, social, and educational value it has, I will just walk away.   There are plenty of places to read, to learn, to share, to connect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, Instead of cruising Twitter every morning and worrying about what it might become, I’ve been spending time on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.duolingo.com/learn&quot;&gt;Duolingo&lt;/a&gt;, trying to relearn my high school Spanish.  I feel better after doing this than I have ever felt after spending time on Twitter.  I will probably continue to drift away from Twitter towards more learning, thinking, and positive communication venues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;progressive-buyers-guide&quot;&gt;Progressive Buyer’s Guide&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the Progressive Voter’s Guide (&lt;a href=&quot;https://progressivevotersguide.com&quot;&gt;https://progressivevotersguide.com&lt;/a&gt;).  It is not my sole source of voting info, but it is a very helpful and concise guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also like the sustainable seafood guide (&lt;a href=&quot;https://oceana.org/living-blue-sustainable-seafood-guide/&quot;&gt;https://oceana.org/living-blue-sustainable-seafood-guide/&lt;/a&gt;).  When I have useful info on products and their impact, I like to make the most beneficial choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I had a Progressive Buyer’s Guide.  When I go to buy a car, or book a trip, or buy an appliance, or subscribe to a service, or whatever — where is that money going?  What political efforts are supported by that company or by its principals?  What states are benefiting most from my expenditure?  Do I have alternatives available that would direct money towards more progressive states or more progressive political efforts?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, I found out this year that, not only had ATT and ATT executives donated to Republican candidates, but ATT helped to fund the establishment of the right wing OAN news network.  I don’t need to fund that.  I happily made the switch to T-Mobile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some elements I would want as part of an effort to build a progressive buyer’s guide:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A system to track a product’s source by state, company.  What % of this car is produced in what state (or finer grained region) by what company?  I’d want to support community involvement, ultimately will want to tap a network of people providing this info.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A system to track a company’s donations and the donations of executives.  Most of this is already public at the FEC website or Opensecrets.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A progressive weighting of states, politicians, PACs, etc, and an algorithm to sum those into a total weighting for a product.  It is likely that one would want to support multiple ratings — IE a total progressive rating, a climate change rating, an income inequality rating, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A front end to display a weighting for a product.  And for a given product, show the more progressive alternatives.  You want a certain suv?   This alternative has more content produced in more progressive states, and the execs give less to retrogressive candidates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;random&quot;&gt;Random&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://steampipe.io&quot;&gt;Steampipe.io&lt;/a&gt; – a sql interface on top of all kinds of cloud resources.  Kind of cool.  As Sam says, software engineers love grand unification schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this era of heightened political conflict, why are the US Senators from the state of Washington so nearly invisbile?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not like pickles.  But I have great admiration for the pickle lobby who have somehow convinced everyone to put pickles with every sandwich ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the cryptocurrency luminaries — &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/saylor/status/1307029562321231873?s=21&amp;amp;t=dLhUbUOCawQ0lxu-uGogng&quot;&gt;“Bitcoin is a swarm of cyber hornets serving the goddess of wisdom”&lt;/a&gt;.  I have sometimes handwaved in some presentations, but I am a handwaving amateur.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Well it has been a while since I have posted any observations. I have improved my pickleball game tho.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – The Overnight Guest, Only the Rich Can Play, Ring Shout, Death of Expertise</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/overnight-guest" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – The Overnight Guest, Only the Rich Can Play, Ring Shout, Death of Expertise" /><published>2022-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/overnight-guest</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/overnight-guest">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60164470-the-overnight-guest&quot;&gt;The Overnight Guest&lt;/a&gt; by Heather Gudenkauf.  A solid but not remarkable mystery.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/58828638-only-the-rich-can-play&quot;&gt;Only The Rich Can Play&lt;/a&gt; by David Wessel.  I expected to be more outraged.  There have been successes and abuses in the Opportunity Zone program.  It is unfortunate that congress is so dysfunctional that it is not possible to tune the program up a little.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/49247242-ring-shout&quot;&gt;Ring Shout&lt;/a&gt; by P. Djèlí Clark.  A unique fantastic tale, a little “Lovecraft Country”, curious which influenced which.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/26720949-the-death-of-expertise&quot;&gt;The Death Of Expertise: The Campaign Against Established Knowledge and Why it Matters&lt;/a&gt; by Thomas Nichols.  Some excellent description of the problem, tho a little bit too much “wah wah wah, why won’t people listen to us”.  I think the burden is on experts to figure out how to persuade and be relevant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Overnight Guest by Heather Gudenkauf. A solid but not remarkable mystery. Only The Rich Can Play by David Wessel. I expected to be more outraged. There have been successes and abuses in the Opportunity Zone program. It is unfortunate that congress is so dysfunctional that it is not possible to tune the program up a little. Ring Shout by P. Djèlí Clark. A unique fantastic tale, a little “Lovecraft Country”, curious which influenced which. The Death Of Expertise: The Campaign Against Established Knowledge and Why it Matters by Thomas Nichols. Some excellent description of the problem, tho a little bit too much “wah wah wah, why won’t people listen to us”. I think the burden is on experts to figure out how to persuade and be relevant.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Dead Companies Walking, Allow Me to Retort, Piranesi</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/dead-companies-retort" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Dead Companies Walking, Allow Me to Retort, Piranesi" /><published>2022-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/dead-companies-retort</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/dead-companies-retort">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22313652-dead-companies-walking&quot;&gt;Dead Companies Walking: How A Hedge Fund Manager Finds Opportunity in Unexpected Places&lt;/a&gt; by Scott Fearon and Jesse Powell.  Some parts of this were great.  The central idea that company failure is a lot more common than success, and that you should have an investment strategy which embraces that, is a good idea, though I don’t have the appetite for risk required (tho maybe I should invest in a short fund).  His portrayal of short sellers as the true heroes of our economy is a bit of a stretch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/58822691-allow-me-to-retort&quot;&gt;Allow Me to Retort: A Black Guy’s Guide to the Constitution&lt;/a&gt; by Elie Mystal.  Fantastic.  Parts of this may antagonize you, and he may go further on some points than I accept, but a well argued and passionate examination.  You have to appreciate his voice and vigor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/53205794-the-last-watch&quot;&gt;The Last Watch&lt;/a&gt; by J.S. Dewes.  Meh. Billed as the Expanse meets Game of Thrones, it is neither.  A vague attempt to set the Game of Thrones Wall in space but uncompelling characters and uncompelling story.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/39929094-hush-hush&quot;&gt;Hush Hush&lt;/a&gt; by Mel Sherrat.  Formulaic, one dimensional characters.  Not worth finishing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/50202953-piranesi&quot;&gt;Piranesi&lt;/a&gt; by Susanna Clarke.  Now this is more like it.  Evocative, strange, fantastic.  Incredibly strange and highly relatable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dead Companies Walking: How A Hedge Fund Manager Finds Opportunity in Unexpected Places by Scott Fearon and Jesse Powell. Some parts of this were great. The central idea that company failure is a lot more common than success, and that you should have an investment strategy which embraces that, is a good idea, though I don’t have the appetite for risk required (tho maybe I should invest in a short fund). His portrayal of short sellers as the true heroes of our economy is a bit of a stretch. Allow Me to Retort: A Black Guy’s Guide to the Constitution by Elie Mystal. Fantastic. Parts of this may antagonize you, and he may go further on some points than I accept, but a well argued and passionate examination. You have to appreciate his voice and vigor. The Last Watch by J.S. Dewes. Meh. Billed as the Expanse meets Game of Thrones, it is neither. A vague attempt to set the Game of Thrones Wall in space but uncompelling characters and uncompelling story. Hush Hush by Mel Sherrat. Formulaic, one dimensional characters. Not worth finishing. Piranesi by Susanna Clarke. Now this is more like it. Evocative, strange, fantastic. Incredibly strange and highly relatable.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Deacon King Kong, Don’t Believe It, One Step Too Far, Velocity Weapon, True Believer, Red Sparrow</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/deacon-dont-believe-it-one-step" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Deacon King Kong, Don’t Believe It, One Step Too Far, Velocity Weapon, True Believer, Red Sparrow" /><published>2022-04-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-04-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/deacon-dont-believe-it-one-step</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/deacon-dont-believe-it-one-step">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/51045613-deacon-king-kong&quot;&gt;Deacon King Kong&lt;/a&gt; by James McBride.  Ugh, can’t read.  The central character is so eccentric it is a little cloying.  I moved on.  I am sure based on the good reviews I am missing something, but it was just repellent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36296238-don-t-believe-it&quot;&gt;Don’t Believe It&lt;/a&gt; by Charlie Donlea.  Attempted to cleanse my palate with this, but couldn’t stick with it either.  Just seemed formulaic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/58082194-one-step-too-far&quot;&gt;One Step Too Far&lt;/a&gt; by Lisa Gardner.  Another palate cleansing attempt, more successful.  Imagine if Jack Reacher had no physical skills and was a small woman, but still travelled aimlessly around the country trying to right injustices.  Adventure ensues.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41085049-velocity-weapon&quot;&gt;Velocity Weapon&lt;/a&gt; by Megan E. O’Keefe.  Eh, just average science fiction.  No really new concepts.  Passes the time but that is all.  Didn’t finish.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12139811-the-true-believer&quot;&gt;The True Believer: Thoughts on the Nature of Mass Movements&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Hoffer.  An oldie but a goodie.  71 years old, most of the observations are relevant today.  We may be even more susceptible to populist mass movements today.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/59337703-red-sparrow&quot;&gt;Red Sparrow&lt;/a&gt; by Jason Matthews.  A little long but a great espionage tale.  Betrayals all over the place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Deacon King Kong by James McBride. Ugh, can’t read. The central character is so eccentric it is a little cloying. I moved on. I am sure based on the good reviews I am missing something, but it was just repellent. Don’t Believe It by Charlie Donlea. Attempted to cleanse my palate with this, but couldn’t stick with it either. Just seemed formulaic. One Step Too Far by Lisa Gardner. Another palate cleansing attempt, more successful. Imagine if Jack Reacher had no physical skills and was a small woman, but still travelled aimlessly around the country trying to right injustices. Adventure ensues. Velocity Weapon by Megan E. O’Keefe. Eh, just average science fiction. No really new concepts. Passes the time but that is all. Didn’t finish. The True Believer: Thoughts on the Nature of Mass Movements by Eric Hoffer. An oldie but a goodie. 71 years old, most of the observations are relevant today. We may be even more susceptible to populist mass movements today. Red Sparrow by Jason Matthews. A little long but a great espionage tale. Betrayals all over the place.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Seveneves, War On Cops, To Be Taught, Dark Horse, Code Breaker</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/seveneves-cops" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Seveneves, War On Cops, To Be Taught, Dark Horse, Code Breaker" /><published>2022-04-07T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-04-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/seveneves-cops</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/seveneves-cops">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22816087-seveneves&quot;&gt;Seveneves&lt;/a&gt; by Neal Stephenson.  A ton of interesting ideas.  A long book.  Maybe spend more of this length really digging into some characters and society and the impact of the ideas on both?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/27036577-the-war-on-cops&quot;&gt;The War on Cops: How the New Attack on Law and Order Makes Everyone Less Safe&lt;/a&gt; by Heather MacDonald.  The premise of this book is that our police are under attack by largely black activists which makes us all less safe as it leads to more crime.   The book explores both police activity and the limits activists seek, as well as incarceration and the limits activists seek.  The book fails completely for multiple reasons:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It is not a serious attempt to inform or influence.  No citations, no raw data.  False strawmen, ad hominem arguments.  Inflamatory language.  The book is designed to trigger emotional responses, not rational discussion.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The causes of crime are way upstream from policing or incarceration and the author doesn’t dig into any of that.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The author conflates race and culture and economics and muddies the waters.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43190272-to-be-taught-if-fortunate&quot;&gt;To Be Taught, If Fortunate&lt;/a&gt; by Becky Chambers.  A compact story about the promise and challenges of space exploration.  A quiet story.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/57693476-dark-horse&quot;&gt;Dark Horse&lt;/a&gt; by Gregg Andrew Hurwitz.  OK Reacher-esque tale, tho I would probably just read a Reacher.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/54968118-the-code-breaker&quot;&gt;The Code Breaker: Jennifer Doudna, Gene Editing, and the Future of the Human Race&lt;/a&gt; by Walter Isaacson.  Kind of interesting to read the background on the people involved in the developemnt of CRISPR but I would have liked more technical explanation of how CRISPR actually works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Seveneves by Neal Stephenson. A ton of interesting ideas. A long book. Maybe spend more of this length really digging into some characters and society and the impact of the ideas on both? The War on Cops: How the New Attack on Law and Order Makes Everyone Less Safe by Heather MacDonald. The premise of this book is that our police are under attack by largely black activists which makes us all less safe as it leads to more crime. The book explores both police activity and the limits activists seek, as well as incarceration and the limits activists seek. The book fails completely for multiple reasons: It is not a serious attempt to inform or influence. No citations, no raw data. False strawmen, ad hominem arguments. Inflamatory language. The book is designed to trigger emotional responses, not rational discussion. The causes of crime are way upstream from policing or incarceration and the author doesn’t dig into any of that. The author conflates race and culture and economics and muddies the waters. To Be Taught, If Fortunate by Becky Chambers. A compact story about the promise and challenges of space exploration. A quiet story. Dark Horse by Gregg Andrew Hurwitz. OK Reacher-esque tale, tho I would probably just read a Reacher. The Code Breaker: Jennifer Doudna, Gene Editing, and the Future of the Human Race by Walter Isaacson. Kind of interesting to read the background on the people involved in the developemnt of CRISPR but I would have liked more technical explanation of how CRISPR actually works.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Empire of Pain, This Is How They Tell Me the World Ends, We Are Legion, Factory Girls</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/pain-world" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Empire of Pain, This Is How They Tell Me the World Ends, We Are Legion, Factory Girls" /><published>2022-03-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-03-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/pain-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/pain-world">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43868109-empire-of-pain&quot;&gt;Empire of Pain: The Secret History of the Sackler Dynasty&lt;/a&gt; by Patrick Radden Keefe.  I did not realize how much this was a story of a marketing dynasty. A triumph of marketing and business development over morality and good sense.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/49247043-this-is-how-they-tell-me-the-world-ends&quot;&gt;This Is How They Tell Me the World Ends: The Cyberweapons Arms Race&lt;/a&gt; by Nicole Perlroth.  The entire internet is compromised and we better get cracking to fix it.  Our software and internet industries were created by optimists and enthusiasts, but increasingly are inhabited by bad actors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A thread across both these books – it is a great strength of our free market economy that we allow new companies to easily create new offerings and enter the market – but we don’t have great mechanisms for assigning responsibility for the societal problems they may create.  The innovators get rich and move on, society is left with the huge costs of opioid addictions or the huge costs of easily hackable software systems.  The innovators should bear more responsibility, but this is a hard problem to fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After these two books, I needed some lighter fare:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/32109569-we-are-legion-we-are-bob&quot;&gt;We Are Legion (We Are Bob)&lt;/a&gt; by Dennis E. Taylor.  A lighthearted tale of galaxy exploration by an idiosyncratic post-human AI and its clones.  There are many more books in the series and I enjoyed, but probably won’t continue as I have too many other books on the pile:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then a transition back to more serious fare:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8247140-factory-girls&quot;&gt;Factory Girls: From Village to City in a Changing China&lt;/a&gt; by Leslie T. Chang.  Deep dive into the lives of migrant workers in modern China.  A real “wild wild west” economic scene, inside of a very traditional hierarchical society.  Interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Empire of Pain: The Secret History of the Sackler Dynasty by Patrick Radden Keefe. I did not realize how much this was a story of a marketing dynasty. A triumph of marketing and business development over morality and good sense. This Is How They Tell Me the World Ends: The Cyberweapons Arms Race by Nicole Perlroth. The entire internet is compromised and we better get cracking to fix it. Our software and internet industries were created by optimists and enthusiasts, but increasingly are inhabited by bad actors.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Salvation Sequence, Righteous Mind, Crooked Tree</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/salvation-righteous-etc" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Salvation Sequence, Righteous Mind, Crooked Tree" /><published>2022-03-07T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-03-07T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/salvation-righteous-etc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/salvation-righteous-etc">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/37684919-salvation&quot;&gt;Salvation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/44020966-salvation-lost&quot;&gt;Salvation Lost&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/50154683-the-saints-of-salvation&quot;&gt;The Saints of Salvation&lt;/a&gt; by Peter F. Hamilton.  Far reaching space opera, tons of far-fetched ideas.  Solid and fun.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15992204-the-righteous-mind&quot;&gt;The Righteous Mind&lt;/a&gt; by Jonathan Haidt.  Interesting argument about the evolutionary basis of morality and religion, and the implications for political arguments.  Makes the strong argument that the mainstream Democratic party has a substantial problem in appealing to large parts of the population.  Certainly thought provoking.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/54236137-a-crooked-tree&quot;&gt;A Crooked Tree&lt;/a&gt; by Una Mannion.  A tired mother acts rashly and events ensue that destroy lives.  Really grew on me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Salvation, Salvation Lost, The Saints of Salvation by Peter F. Hamilton. Far reaching space opera, tons of far-fetched ideas. Solid and fun. The Righteous Mind by Jonathan Haidt. Interesting argument about the evolutionary basis of morality and religion, and the implications for political arguments. Makes the strong argument that the mainstream Democratic party has a substantial problem in appealing to large parts of the population. Certainly thought provoking. A Crooked Tree by Una Mannion. A tired mother acts rashly and events ensue that destroy lives. Really grew on me.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – CivilWarLand in Bad Decline, All This Could Be Yours, Blood River</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/civilwarland-etc" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – CivilWarLand in Bad Decline, All This Could Be Yours, Blood River" /><published>2022-02-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-02-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/civilwarland-etc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/civilwarland-etc">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28747.CivilWarLand_in_Bad_Decline&quot;&gt;CivilWarLand in Bad Decline&lt;/a&gt; by George Saunders.  Well written but just not my taste, too much farce.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43261190-all-this-could-be-yours&quot;&gt;All This Could Be Yours&lt;/a&gt; by Jami Attenberg.  A patriarch dies and all the family sh$t comes out, and boy did he damage everybody in the family.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/19010711-blood-river&quot;&gt;Blood River&lt;/a&gt; by Tim Butcher.  The author recreates Stanley’s trip through the Congo.  Illuminating and saddening and terrifying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">CivilWarLand in Bad Decline by George Saunders. Well written but just not my taste, too much farce. All This Could Be Yours by Jami Attenberg. A patriarch dies and all the family sh$t comes out, and boy did he damage everybody in the family. Blood River by Tim Butcher. The author recreates Stanley’s trip through the Congo. Illuminating and saddening and terrifying.</summary></entry></feed>