<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-04-25T20:07:18-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">A Little Ludwig Goes a Long Way</title><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Dead Companies Walking, Allow Me to Retort, Piranesi</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/dead-companies-retort" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Dead Companies Walking, Allow Me to Retort, Piranesi" /><published>2022-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/dead-companies-retort</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/dead-companies-retort">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22313652-dead-companies-walking&quot;&gt;Dead Companies Walking: How A Hedge Fund Manager Finds Opportunity in Unexpected Places&lt;/a&gt; by Scott Fearon and Jesse Powell.  Some parts of this were great.  The central idea that company failure is a lot more common than success, and that you should have an investment strategy which embraces that, is a good idea, though I don’t have the appetite for risk required (tho maybe I should invest in a short fund).  His portrayal of short sellers as the true heroes of our economy is a bit of a stretch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/58822691-allow-me-to-retort&quot;&gt;Allow Me to Retort: A Black Guy’s Guide to the Constitution&lt;/a&gt; by Elie Mystal.  Fantastic.  Parts of this may antagonize you, and he may go further on some points than I accept, but a well argued and passionate examination.  You have to appreciate his voice and vigor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/53205794-the-last-watch&quot;&gt;The Last Watch&lt;/a&gt; by J.S. Dewes.  Meh. Billed as the Expanse meets Game of Thrones, it is neither.  A vague attempt to set the Game of Thrones Wall in space but uncompelling characters and uncompelling story.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/39929094-hush-hush&quot;&gt;Hush Hush&lt;/a&gt; by Mel Sherrat.  Formulaic, one dimensional characters.  Not worth finishing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/50202953-piranesi&quot;&gt;Piranesi&lt;/a&gt; by Susanna Clarke.  Now this is more like it.  Evocative, strange, fantastic.  Incredibly strange and highly relatable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dead Companies Walking: How A Hedge Fund Manager Finds Opportunity in Unexpected Places by Scott Fearon and Jesse Powell. Some parts of this were great. The central idea that company failure is a lot more common than success, and that you should have an investment strategy which embraces that, is a good idea, though I don’t have the appetite for risk required (tho maybe I should invest in a short fund). His portrayal of short sellers as the true heroes of our economy is a bit of a stretch. Allow Me to Retort: A Black Guy’s Guide to the Constitution by Elie Mystal. Fantastic. Parts of this may antagonize you, and he may go further on some points than I accept, but a well argued and passionate examination. You have to appreciate his voice and vigor. The Last Watch by J.S. Dewes. Meh. Billed as the Expanse meets Game of Thrones, it is neither. A vague attempt to set the Game of Thrones Wall in space but uncompelling characters and uncompelling story. Hush Hush by Mel Sherrat. Formulaic, one dimensional characters. Not worth finishing. Piranesi by Susanna Clarke. Now this is more like it. Evocative, strange, fantastic. Incredibly strange and highly relatable.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Deacon King Kong, Don’t Believe It, One Step Too Far, Velocity Weapon, True Believer, Red Sparrow</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/deacon-dont-believe-it-one-step" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Deacon King Kong, Don’t Believe It, One Step Too Far, Velocity Weapon, True Believer, Red Sparrow" /><published>2022-04-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-04-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/deacon-dont-believe-it-one-step</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/deacon-dont-believe-it-one-step">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/51045613-deacon-king-kong&quot;&gt;Deacon King Kong&lt;/a&gt; by James McBride.  Ugh, can’t read.  The central character is so eccentric it is a little cloying.  I moved on.  I am sure based on the good reviews I am missing something, but it was just repellent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36296238-don-t-believe-it&quot;&gt;Don’t Believe It&lt;/a&gt; by Charlie Donlea.  Attempted to cleanse my palate with this, but couldn’t stick with it either.  Just seemed formulaic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/58082194-one-step-too-far&quot;&gt;One Step Too Far&lt;/a&gt; by Lisa Gardner.  Another palate cleansing attempt, more successful.  Imagine if Jack Reacher had no physical skills and was a small woman, but still travelled aimlessly around the country trying to right injustices.  Adventure ensues.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41085049-velocity-weapon&quot;&gt;Velocity Weapon&lt;/a&gt; by Megan E. O’Keefe.  Eh, just average science fiction.  No really new concepts.  Passes the time but that is all.  Didn’t finish.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12139811-the-true-believer&quot;&gt;The True Believer: Thoughts on the Nature of Mass Movements&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Hoffer.  An oldie but a goodie.  71 years old, most of the observations are relevant today.  We may be even more susceptible to populist mass movements today.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/59337703-red-sparrow&quot;&gt;Red Sparrow&lt;/a&gt; by Jason Matthews.  A little long but a great espionage tale.  Betrayals all over the place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Deacon King Kong by James McBride. Ugh, can’t read. The central character is so eccentric it is a little cloying. I moved on. I am sure based on the good reviews I am missing something, but it was just repellent. Don’t Believe It by Charlie Donlea. Attempted to cleanse my palate with this, but couldn’t stick with it either. Just seemed formulaic. One Step Too Far by Lisa Gardner. Another palate cleansing attempt, more successful. Imagine if Jack Reacher had no physical skills and was a small woman, but still travelled aimlessly around the country trying to right injustices. Adventure ensues. Velocity Weapon by Megan E. O’Keefe. Eh, just average science fiction. No really new concepts. Passes the time but that is all. Didn’t finish. The True Believer: Thoughts on the Nature of Mass Movements by Eric Hoffer. An oldie but a goodie. 71 years old, most of the observations are relevant today. We may be even more susceptible to populist mass movements today. Red Sparrow by Jason Matthews. A little long but a great espionage tale. Betrayals all over the place.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Seveneves, War On Cops, To Be Taught, Dark Horse, Code Breaker</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/seveneves-cops" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Seveneves, War On Cops, To Be Taught, Dark Horse, Code Breaker" /><published>2022-04-07T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-04-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/seveneves-cops</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/seveneves-cops">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22816087-seveneves&quot;&gt;Seveneves&lt;/a&gt; by Neal Stephenson.  A ton of interesting ideas.  A long book.  Maybe spend more of this length really digging into some characters and society and the impact of the ideas on both?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/27036577-the-war-on-cops&quot;&gt;The War on Cops: How the New Attack on Law and Order Makes Everyone Less Safe&lt;/a&gt; by Heather MacDonald.  The premise of this book is that our police are under attack by largely black activists which makes us all less safe as it leads to more crime.   The book explores both police activity and the limits activists seek, as well as incarceration and the limits activists seek.  The book fails completely for multiple reasons:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It is not a serious attempt to inform or influence.  No citations, no raw data.  False strawmen, ad hominem arguments.  Inflamatory language.  The book is designed to trigger emotional responses, not rational discussion.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The causes of crime are way upstream from policing or incarceration and the author doesn’t dig into any of that.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The author conflates race and culture and economics and muddies the waters.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43190272-to-be-taught-if-fortunate&quot;&gt;To Be Taught, If Fortunate&lt;/a&gt; by Becky Chambers.  A compact story about the promise and challenges of space exploration.  A quiet story.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/57693476-dark-horse&quot;&gt;Dark Horse&lt;/a&gt; by Gregg Andrew Hurwitz.  OK Reacher-esque tale, tho I would probably just read a Reacher.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/54968118-the-code-breaker&quot;&gt;The Code Breaker: Jennifer Doudna, Gene Editing, and the Future of the Human Race&lt;/a&gt; by Walter Isaacson.  Kind of interesting to read the background on the people involved in the developemnt of CRISPR but I would have liked more technical explanation of how CRISPR actually works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Seveneves by Neal Stephenson. A ton of interesting ideas. A long book. Maybe spend more of this length really digging into some characters and society and the impact of the ideas on both? The War on Cops: How the New Attack on Law and Order Makes Everyone Less Safe by Heather MacDonald. The premise of this book is that our police are under attack by largely black activists which makes us all less safe as it leads to more crime. The book explores both police activity and the limits activists seek, as well as incarceration and the limits activists seek. The book fails completely for multiple reasons: It is not a serious attempt to inform or influence. No citations, no raw data. False strawmen, ad hominem arguments. Inflamatory language. The book is designed to trigger emotional responses, not rational discussion. The causes of crime are way upstream from policing or incarceration and the author doesn’t dig into any of that. The author conflates race and culture and economics and muddies the waters. To Be Taught, If Fortunate by Becky Chambers. A compact story about the promise and challenges of space exploration. A quiet story. Dark Horse by Gregg Andrew Hurwitz. OK Reacher-esque tale, tho I would probably just read a Reacher. The Code Breaker: Jennifer Doudna, Gene Editing, and the Future of the Human Race by Walter Isaacson. Kind of interesting to read the background on the people involved in the developemnt of CRISPR but I would have liked more technical explanation of how CRISPR actually works.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Empire of Pain, This Is How They Tell Me the World Ends, We Are Legion, Factory Girls</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/pain-world" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Empire of Pain, This Is How They Tell Me the World Ends, We Are Legion, Factory Girls" /><published>2022-03-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-03-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/pain-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/pain-world">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43868109-empire-of-pain&quot;&gt;Empire of Pain: The Secret History of the Sackler Dynasty&lt;/a&gt; by Patrick Radden Keefe.  I did not realize how much this was a story of a marketing dynasty. A triumph of marketing and business development over morality and good sense.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/49247043-this-is-how-they-tell-me-the-world-ends&quot;&gt;This Is How They Tell Me the World Ends: The Cyberweapons Arms Race&lt;/a&gt; by Nicole Perlroth.  The entire internet is compromised and we better get cracking to fix it.  Our software and internet industries were created by optimists and enthusiasts, but increasingly are inhabited by bad actors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A thread across both these books – it is a great strength of our free market economy that we allow new companies to easily create new offerings and enter the market – but we don’t have great mechanisms for assigning responsibility for the societal problems they may create.  The innovators get rich and move on, society is left with the huge costs of opioid addictions or the huge costs of easily hackable software systems.  The innovators should bear more responsibility, but this is a hard problem to fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After these two books, I needed some lighter fare:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/32109569-we-are-legion-we-are-bob&quot;&gt;We Are Legion (We Are Bob)&lt;/a&gt; by Dennis E. Taylor.  A lighthearted tale of galaxy exploration by an idiosyncratic post-human AI and its clones.  There are many more books in the series and I enjoyed, but probably won’t continue as I have too many other books on the pile:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then a transition back to more serious fare:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8247140-factory-girls&quot;&gt;Factory Girls: From Village to City in a Changing China&lt;/a&gt; by Leslie T. Chang.  Deep dive into the lives of migrant workers in modern China.  A real “wild wild west” economic scene, inside of a very traditional hierarchical society.  Interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Empire of Pain: The Secret History of the Sackler Dynasty by Patrick Radden Keefe. I did not realize how much this was a story of a marketing dynasty. A triumph of marketing and business development over morality and good sense. This Is How They Tell Me the World Ends: The Cyberweapons Arms Race by Nicole Perlroth. The entire internet is compromised and we better get cracking to fix it. Our software and internet industries were created by optimists and enthusiasts, but increasingly are inhabited by bad actors.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Salvation Sequence, Righteous Mind, Crooked Tree</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/salvation-righteous-etc" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Salvation Sequence, Righteous Mind, Crooked Tree" /><published>2022-03-07T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-03-07T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/salvation-righteous-etc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/salvation-righteous-etc">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/37684919-salvation&quot;&gt;Salvation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/44020966-salvation-lost&quot;&gt;Salvation Lost&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/50154683-the-saints-of-salvation&quot;&gt;The Saints of Salvation&lt;/a&gt; by Peter F. Hamilton.  Far reaching space opera, tons of far-fetched ideas.  Solid and fun.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15992204-the-righteous-mind&quot;&gt;The Righteous Mind&lt;/a&gt; by Jonathan Haidt.  Interesting argument about the evolutionary basis of morality and religion, and the implications for political arguments.  Makes the strong argument that the mainstream Democratic party has a substantial problem in appealing to large parts of the population.  Certainly thought provoking.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/54236137-a-crooked-tree&quot;&gt;A Crooked Tree&lt;/a&gt; by Una Mannion.  A tired mother acts rashly and events ensue that destroy lives.  Really grew on me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Salvation, Salvation Lost, The Saints of Salvation by Peter F. Hamilton. Far reaching space opera, tons of far-fetched ideas. Solid and fun. The Righteous Mind by Jonathan Haidt. Interesting argument about the evolutionary basis of morality and religion, and the implications for political arguments. Makes the strong argument that the mainstream Democratic party has a substantial problem in appealing to large parts of the population. Certainly thought provoking. A Crooked Tree by Una Mannion. A tired mother acts rashly and events ensue that destroy lives. Really grew on me.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – CivilWarLand in Bad Decline, All This Could Be Yours, Blood River</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/civilwarland-etc" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – CivilWarLand in Bad Decline, All This Could Be Yours, Blood River" /><published>2022-02-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-02-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/civilwarland-etc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/civilwarland-etc">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28747.CivilWarLand_in_Bad_Decline&quot;&gt;CivilWarLand in Bad Decline&lt;/a&gt; by George Saunders.  Well written but just not my taste, too much farce.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43261190-all-this-could-be-yours&quot;&gt;All This Could Be Yours&lt;/a&gt; by Jami Attenberg.  A patriarch dies and all the family sh$t comes out, and boy did he damage everybody in the family.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/19010711-blood-river&quot;&gt;Blood River&lt;/a&gt; by Tim Butcher.  The author recreates Stanley’s trip through the Congo.  Illuminating and saddening and terrifying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">CivilWarLand in Bad Decline by George Saunders. Well written but just not my taste, too much farce. All This Could Be Yours by Jami Attenberg. A patriarch dies and all the family sh$t comes out, and boy did he damage everybody in the family. Blood River by Tim Butcher. The author recreates Stanley’s trip through the Congo. Illuminating and saddening and terrifying.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Roundup of ideas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/meanderings" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Roundup of ideas" /><published>2022-02-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-02-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/meanderings</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/meanderings">&lt;p&gt;I am continually disappointed by the number of &lt;strong&gt;“secure email portals”&lt;/strong&gt; i am asked to sign into.  Every medical provider, every financial institution.  And each of these seem to use a different underlying implementation.  Some of the smaller medical providers seem to use some SAAS solutiuons, tho these seem like very obscure SAAS solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most recent one is from a very large insurance provider who should probably know better.  Their “security questions” are particularly humorous — “What is the longest book you have ever read”, “What’s your dream job”, “What’s your least favorite city”, etc.  A) I will never remember what I entered for these, B) the answers are not stable over any reasonable amount of time.  There are a lot of crappy cities I haven’t been to, a lot of books I haven’t read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is too bad we can’t have secure end-to-end email like we do messaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quantamagazine.org/the-year-in-biology-20211221/&quot;&gt;The Year in Biology&lt;/a&gt; – a &lt;strong&gt;great overview of biology advances&lt;/strong&gt;, especially for biology ignoramuses like me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to do a deep trial of &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsidian.md&quot;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.dendron.so&quot;&gt;Dendron&lt;/a&gt;.  They seem right up my alley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/charlesfitz&quot;&gt;CharlesF&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geekwire.com/2022/the-great-startup-reset-why-founders-should-prepare-for-lower-valuations/&quot;&gt;preparing for lower valuations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.profgalloway.com/the-algebra-of-wealth-2/&quot;&gt;Scott Galloway on the importance of choosing your sector&lt;/a&gt;:  key quotes: “Sector dynamics will trump your talent…someone of average talent at Google has done better over the past decade than someone great at General Motors…Look for the best wave to ride”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kevinsmokler.com/2022/01/25/in-praising-of-listening-through-every-album-by-your-favorite-artist/&quot;&gt;Listening through&lt;/a&gt; by Kevin Smokler.  Great way to understand an artist.  I have of course done this for the Beatles, Led Zeppelin, the Rolling Stones, but starting to use it with other lesser known artistis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://noahpinion.substack.com/p/a-new-industrialist-roundup&quot;&gt;Noah Smith on progressive industrialism&lt;/a&gt;.  A necessary and compelling part of a progressive view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nice thread on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HarryStebbings/status/1490516792615313412?s=20&amp;amp;t=4fOLo7L7i5RRLro1Sw-ydg&quot;&gt;modest purchases that have had a big impact&lt;/a&gt; on people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning how to do timelapse photography on the Canon EOS R or 5R.  Thankfully there are a number of cookbooks — &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.matjoez.com/2018/10/08/is-the-canon-eos-r-a-good-timelapse-camera/&quot;&gt;the simple way&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CkiB51fsi2M&quot;&gt;the harder way&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I am continually disappointed by the number of “secure email portals” i am asked to sign into. Every medical provider, every financial institution. And each of these seem to use a different underlying implementation. Some of the smaller medical providers seem to use some SAAS solutiuons, tho these seem like very obscure SAAS solutions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Words Like Loaded Pistols, Ideas Have Consequences, New Wilderness, Nuclear Express</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/words-ideas" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Words Like Loaded Pistols, Ideas Have Consequences, New Wilderness, Nuclear Express" /><published>2022-01-27T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-27T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/words-ideas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/words-ideas">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/30009896-words-like-loaded-pistols&quot;&gt;Words Like Loaded Pistols: Rhetoric from Aristotle to Obama&lt;/a&gt; by Sam Leith.  Gosh I wish I had read this earlier in my life, or studied rhetoric.  So much I don’t know about effective communication.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/5665.Ideas_Have_Consequences&quot;&gt;Ideas Have Consequences&lt;/a&gt; by Richard M. Weaver.  So, there are some seriously dated and bad cultural takes in here, but the core ideas are provocative – the Western world has slowly lost its sense of shared mission and values, which has resulted in our current political morass.  Published in 1948, but just as relevant today, as long as you can get past some of the objectionable content.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/57238009-the-new-wilderness&quot;&gt;The New Wilderness&lt;/a&gt; by Diane Cook.  I like speculative fiction when it shows real people adapting to a new situation. These kind of thought experiments can teach us something. But when the characters don’t seem like real people at all, and behave in weird-ass ways, I lose interest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/4231006-the-nuclear-express&quot;&gt;The Nuclear Express: A Political History of the Bomb and Its Proliferation&lt;/a&gt; by Thomas Reed and Danny Stillman.  Interesting details on how proliferation has happened.  The political conjecturing is weak and spy thriller-ish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Words Like Loaded Pistols: Rhetoric from Aristotle to Obama by Sam Leith. Gosh I wish I had read this earlier in my life, or studied rhetoric. So much I don’t know about effective communication. Ideas Have Consequences by Richard M. Weaver. So, there are some seriously dated and bad cultural takes in here, but the core ideas are provocative – the Western world has slowly lost its sense of shared mission and values, which has resulted in our current political morass. Published in 1948, but just as relevant today, as long as you can get past some of the objectionable content. The New Wilderness by Diane Cook. I like speculative fiction when it shows real people adapting to a new situation. These kind of thought experiments can teach us something. But when the characters don’t seem like real people at all, and behave in weird-ass ways, I lose interest. The Nuclear Express: A Political History of the Bomb and Its Proliferation by Thomas Reed and Danny Stillman. Interesting details on how proliferation has happened. The political conjecturing is weak and spy thriller-ish.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How important is your job to your company?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/career-advice" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How important is your job to your company?" /><published>2022-01-17T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/career-advice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/career-advice">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Carnage4Life&quot;&gt;Dare Obasanjo&lt;/a&gt; has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Carnage4Life/status/1483073446045118464?s=20&quot;&gt;nice post with a simple framework for evaluating job alternatives&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It led me to reflect on my own job selection logic.  When I started my career back in the 80s, I was working in the Midwest, and it was a time of industrial restructuring and downsizing.  Layoffs were unfortunately common.  A very smart colleague at Booz-Allen, Bert Jones (who I have lost contact with), shared these simple ideas with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to avoid layoffs, you should&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;work in the most important business (or businesses) to the company.  This means learning to read company financials and really understanding where revenues, margins, and growth comes from.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and in that business, have a job either making things or selling things.  Every other job is subject to downsizing.  But if you are making or selling the most important things to the company, you are pretty safe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These points were useful more generally throughout my career.  Even when I was at Microsoft during a period of heady growth, and layoffs were not a threat, these factors impacted directly how much support I received – the closer I was to the core Windows (or Office) businesses, the more support I received, and the more opportunities I had to have an impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this also put me closer to the maelstrom, with greater focus on my performance, and that is not always the right fit, but I enjoyed it at the time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dare Obasanjo has a nice post with a simple framework for evaluating job alternatives.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Biggest Bluff, Rosewater, Lincoln Highway, Mexican Gothic</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/poker-rosewater-lincoln" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Biggest Bluff, Rosewater, Lincoln Highway, Mexican Gothic" /><published>2022-01-08T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/poker-rosewater-lincoln</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/poker-rosewater-lincoln">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/49814228-the-biggest-bluff&quot;&gt;The Biggest Bluff: How I Learned to Pay Attention, Master Myself, and Win&lt;/a&gt; by Maria Konnikova.  Great insight into high-level poker and the thinking skills it teaches.  Very good.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/38362809-rosewater&quot;&gt;Rosewater&lt;/a&gt; by Tade Thompson.  A fun story set in a future Nigeria on a world in which a alien organism has invaded the Earth.  Some good characters, I do wish the author would focus on smaller stories of characters coping in this world, rather than focusing on the big story about the future of the human race and the universe.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/57139780-the-lincoln-highway&quot;&gt;The Lincoln Highway&lt;/a&gt; by Amor Towles.  Amazing adventure of misjudgement, errors, atonement, and resolution for a set of interrelated characters.  Great characters and great construction.  Would be a fantastic mini-series.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/53152636-mexican-gothic&quot;&gt;Mexican Gothic&lt;/a&gt; by Silvia Moreno-Garcia.  I wanted to like it, the setting could have been interesting, but I felt very little of Mexico in the book, and it was just kind of going nowhere.  I gave up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Biggest Bluff: How I Learned to Pay Attention, Master Myself, and Win by Maria Konnikova. Great insight into high-level poker and the thinking skills it teaches. Very good. Rosewater by Tade Thompson. A fun story set in a future Nigeria on a world in which a alien organism has invaded the Earth. Some good characters, I do wish the author would focus on smaller stories of characters coping in this world, rather than focusing on the big story about the future of the human race and the universe. The Lincoln Highway by Amor Towles. Amazing adventure of misjudgement, errors, atonement, and resolution for a set of interrelated characters. Great characters and great construction. Would be a fantastic mini-series. Mexican Gothic by Silvia Moreno-Garcia. I wanted to like it, the setting could have been interesting, but I felt very little of Mexico in the book, and it was just kind of going nowhere. I gave up.</summary></entry></feed>