<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-05-15T14:26:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">A Little Ludwig Goes a Long Way</title><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Rabbi I, Darkness Outside Us, Cronin, Time, Big Things, Owls of the Eastern Ice</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/books-rabbi" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Rabbi I, Darkness Outside Us, Cronin, Time, Big Things, Owls of the Eastern Ice" /><published>2023-05-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-05-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/books-rabbi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/books-rabbi">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25948957-friday-the-rabbi-slept-late&quot;&gt;Friday The Rabbi Slept Late&lt;/a&gt; by Harry Kemelman.  Decided to try this classic series.  Interesting peek into the community, but the story wasn’t compelling.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/55720696-the-darkness-outside-us&quot;&gt;The Darkness Outside Us&lt;/a&gt; by Eliot Schrefer.  Should like it but didn’t like main character and didn’t want to learn any more about him.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13565543-the-twelve&quot;&gt;The Twelve&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/26791287-the-city-of-mirrors&quot;&gt;THe City of Mirrors&lt;/a&gt; by Justin Cronin.  OK I didn’t think I would finish this series but the story was compelling, and the third book really elevated the series.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36442813-the-order-of-time&quot;&gt;The Order of Time&lt;/a&gt; by Carlo Rovelli.  The first third was great, knocking down our perception of time.  Then he lost me with his “blurring” analogy which just didn’t resonate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/61327449-how-big-things-get-done&quot;&gt;How Big Things Get Done&lt;/a&gt; by Bent Flyvbjerg and Dan Gardner.  Initially I reacted poorly to this book, the author is a fan of extensive planning ala “waterfall” software projects, and I have seen too much of that.  But he is a little more nuanced, he embraces the iterative model of software development, his notion of “planning” embraces a lot of the early iteration and trial in software development, he would even include early product releases as planning.  He also discusses the idea that an exhaustive plan can be an impediment to getting great projects done – if we all realized the true costs and time requirements of some projects, we would never start them, they would never get done.  Overall a mostly balanced discussion and he has a lot of data to back his views.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/51542211-owls-of-the-eastern-ice&quot;&gt;Owls of the Eastern Ice&lt;/a&gt; by Jonathan C. Slaght.  Quite the tale of a naturalist’s adventures in the far east of Russia.  I didn’t realize how undeveloped this part of Russia is.  Makes the Olympic Peninsula seem cosmopolitan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Friday The Rabbi Slept Late by Harry Kemelman. Decided to try this classic series. Interesting peek into the community, but the story wasn’t compelling. The Darkness Outside Us by Eliot Schrefer. Should like it but didn’t like main character and didn’t want to learn any more about him. The Twelve and THe City of Mirrors by Justin Cronin. OK I didn’t think I would finish this series but the story was compelling, and the third book really elevated the series. The Order of Time by Carlo Rovelli. The first third was great, knocking down our perception of time. Then he lost me with his “blurring” analogy which just didn’t resonate. How Big Things Get Done by Bent Flyvbjerg and Dan Gardner. Initially I reacted poorly to this book, the author is a fan of extensive planning ala “waterfall” software projects, and I have seen too much of that. But he is a little more nuanced, he embraces the iterative model of software development, his notion of “planning” embraces a lot of the early iteration and trial in software development, he would even include early product releases as planning. He also discusses the idea that an exhaustive plan can be an impediment to getting great projects done – if we all realized the true costs and time requirements of some projects, we would never start them, they would never get done. Overall a mostly balanced discussion and he has a lot of data to back his views. Owls of the Eastern Ice by Jonathan C. Slaght. Quite the tale of a naturalist’s adventures in the far east of Russia. I didn’t realize how undeveloped this part of Russia is. Makes the Olympic Peninsula seem cosmopolitan.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Biology Book, Fluent Forever, The Passage, Pathogenesis, Think Again</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/books-biology-book" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Biology Book, Fluent Forever, The Passage, Pathogenesis, Think Again" /><published>2023-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/books-biology-book</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/books-biology-book">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40864002-a-psalm-for-the-wild-built&quot;&gt;The Biology Book&lt;/a&gt; by Michael C. Gerald and Gloria E. Gerald.  A very approachable walk thru the 250 biggest milestones in biology.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/19661852-fluent-forever&quot;&gt;Fluent Forever&lt;/a&gt; by Gabriel Wyner.  This is a great plainly written guide on learning languages, but has been a little overtaken by the explosion of learning tools and apps.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8145855-the-passage&quot;&gt;The Passage&lt;/a&gt; by Justin Cronin.  A post-apocalyptic vampire-zombie story.  Quite long but I was driven to read it through.  I’d like to read the rest but gosh they are long books.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/61327450-pathogenesis&quot;&gt;Pathogenesis&lt;/a&gt; by Jonathan Kennedy.  How history has been affected by pathogens – I knew some of this story, and books like Guns, Germs, and Steel have covered some of this territory, but there were some new things for me in here – I didn’t understand how malaria and yellow fever resistence helped drive the slave trade.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/55539565-think-again&quot;&gt;Think Again: The Power of Knowing What You Don’t Know&lt;/a&gt; by Adam Grant.  I want to like this book.  There is a powerful message in here.  But the author’s continued use of misdirection and reveals is just kind of annoying, almost feels disrespectful to the reader.  I don’t think he had ill intent but it was offputting for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Biology Book by Michael C. Gerald and Gloria E. Gerald. A very approachable walk thru the 250 biggest milestones in biology. Fluent Forever by Gabriel Wyner. This is a great plainly written guide on learning languages, but has been a little overtaken by the explosion of learning tools and apps. The Passage by Justin Cronin. A post-apocalyptic vampire-zombie story. Quite long but I was driven to read it through. I’d like to read the rest but gosh they are long books. Pathogenesis by Jonathan Kennedy. How history has been affected by pathogens – I knew some of this story, and books like Guns, Germs, and Steel have covered some of this territory, but there were some new things for me in here – I didn’t understand how malaria and yellow fever resistence helped drive the slave trade. Think Again: The Power of Knowing What You Don’t Know by Adam Grant. I want to like this book. There is a powerful message in here. But the author’s continued use of misdirection and reveals is just kind of annoying, almost feels disrespectful to the reader. I don’t think he had ill intent but it was offputting for me.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">We just finished a home remodel, and the state of the smart home is not good</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/home-system-mess" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We just finished a home remodel, and the state of the smart home is not good" /><published>2023-04-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-04-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/home-system-mess</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/home-system-mess">&lt;p&gt;(An aside – I have let my writing lapse due to other projects in the last 6 months.  And that is a shame, because writing is the best way to cement your learning, to tease out your thinking, and to kickstart engagement with others.  I see people that set goals to write 1000 words a day.  A high bar but a good one.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We just are wrapping up a remodelling project.  Top of mind this week is all the smart tech in the home and the attention they demand.  Every appliance and device maker has the central idea that their device is the most important device ever, and that you should dedicate your day to admiring it and servicing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Washers and dryers with their loud “cycle finished” alarms, because of course nothing is more important in my day that knowing when a cycle finishes, especially at 10 PM in the middle of a movie, or at 1 AM when you are in bed.  And the UX to turn off the alarm is goooooofy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dishwashers with “cycle finished” alarm to rival the smoke alarm in persistence, they just go on and on and on.  THe manufacturer did so much work to make the dishwasher itself quiet, only to blare an alarm saying “I’m Done!!!  Come Celebrate!!  NOW NOW NOW!!”.  And again the UX to turn off is terrible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Smart thermostats that want to be the star of the room – big black obelisks with garish color displays.  Most homeowners want their thermostats to disappear.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The smart vacuum with the speaker and voice that yells at me at 1AM to “plug me in now” because it wasn’t seated right on the charger.  I just about wet my pants that night.  I have a smart vacuum because I don’t want to think about vacuuming, not because I want to be yelled at by a vacuum.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;OK the “you left the fridge door open” alarm is sensible and I am glad for that one.  But it is the exception.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The smart doorbell that by default sends you an alert for every motion at your door – so god forbid your doorbell camera faces the street or trees or something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost all the manufacturers recognize that the phone is a key part of everyone’s life, so they all build their own apps for their devices.  They don’t embrace Homekit or other standards, because they want to own the relationship with the consumer.  So you get a flotilla of apps, each with their own UX and object model and interaction style and notification control.  Some are beyond goofy.  I have a whole page of them on my phone now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think any of us really want a refrigerator app and a stovetop app and a icemaker app and a thermostat app (three in my house because we have Trane and Honeywell thermostats and a minisplit!)  We really want a home app and everything to click into it, and a common way to control notifications, to group things, to automate, etc.  I’m a nerd so I of course install all the apps, but the regular humans in my household want nothing to do with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these separate apps do not build the brand loyalty that the manufacturers want – every time I have to run the Honeywell app, it is time lost, and it just reminds me what jerks the Honeywell product managers are and how little they think of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of this mess is because there is no established practice of system architecture in the home.  We have great architects who think thru the physical design of the house and the mechanical systems.  But I am not seeing the same leadership in digital and electrical infrastructure in the home.  We have a jumble of security, audio, cat6, low voltage, and other wiring.  A jumble of wireless protocols for data, for proprietary security and control systems.  A jumble of apps,  jumble of logins and accounts and cloud services  There is no design here.  The architects and contractors leave it up to subcontractors who just jam stuff in.  It is all a little embarrassing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">(An aside – I have let my writing lapse due to other projects in the last 6 months. And that is a shame, because writing is the best way to cement your learning, to tease out your thinking, and to kickstart engagement with others. I see people that set goals to write 1000 words a day. A high bar but a good one.)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Monk and Robot, Terminal Alliance, How Asia Works, Data Detective, Delta-V, Critical Mass</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/books-robot-monk" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Monk and Robot, Terminal Alliance, How Asia Works, Data Detective, Delta-V, Critical Mass" /><published>2023-04-05T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-04-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/books-robot-monk</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/books-robot-monk">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40864002-a-psalm-for-the-wild-built&quot;&gt;A Psalm for the Wild-built&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40864030-a-prayer-for-the-crown-shy&quot;&gt;A Prayer for the Crown-Shy&lt;/a&gt; by Becky Chambers.  Brilliant little stories about what it really is to be human and how to accept others.  Can’t recommend highly enough.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/31363503-terminal-alliance&quot;&gt;Terminal Alliance&lt;/a&gt; by Jim C. Hines.  Engaging space opera.  No new ground covered but likable characters and good plotting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/48549206-how-asia-works&quot;&gt;How Asia Works&lt;/a&gt; by Joe Studwell.  A bit dense but a very good analysis of country development in Asia – what has worked, what has failed.  A lot of excellent analysis of the policies that led to success in Taiwan, South Korea, and Japan.   I loved this line – “At the industrial policy-making level, what stands out with the benefit of hindsight is that there was almost no role played in Japan, Korea, or Taiwan by economists.”  Most of the advice by big-brained western consultants and agencies has been dead wrong.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/53605067-the-data-detective&quot;&gt;The Data Detective: Ten Easy Rules to Make Sense of Statistics&lt;/a&gt; by Tim Harford. An ok look at how to better understand and validate statistics.  Tho probably won’t stick with me the way The Black Swan or Superforecasting have stuck with me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40888428-delta-v&quot;&gt;Delta-V&lt;/a&gt; adn &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60234192-critical-mass&quot;&gt;Critical Mass&lt;/a&gt; by Daniel Suarez.  The story of the bootstrapping of the first space-resident society off Earth.  A lot of fun technology forecasting, but characters and plot were kind of secondary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A Psalm for the Wild-built and A Prayer for the Crown-Shy by Becky Chambers. Brilliant little stories about what it really is to be human and how to accept others. Can’t recommend highly enough. Terminal Alliance by Jim C. Hines. Engaging space opera. No new ground covered but likable characters and good plotting. How Asia Works by Joe Studwell. A bit dense but a very good analysis of country development in Asia – what has worked, what has failed. A lot of excellent analysis of the policies that led to success in Taiwan, South Korea, and Japan. I loved this line – “At the industrial policy-making level, what stands out with the benefit of hindsight is that there was almost no role played in Japan, Korea, or Taiwan by economists.” Most of the advice by big-brained western consultants and agencies has been dead wrong. The Data Detective: Ten Easy Rules to Make Sense of Statistics by Tim Harford. An ok look at how to better understand and validate statistics. Tho probably won’t stick with me the way The Black Swan or Superforecasting have stuck with me. Delta-V adn Critical Mass by Daniel Suarez. The story of the bootstrapping of the first space-resident society off Earth. A lot of fun technology forecasting, but characters and plot were kind of secondary.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – G-Man, Gender Queer, She, Blood and Oil, Blood of the Lamb</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/books-gman-blood-she-lamb" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – G-Man, Gender Queer, She, Blood and Oil, Blood of the Lamb" /><published>2023-03-03T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-03-03T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/books-gman-blood-she-lamb</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/books-gman-blood-she-lamb">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/61182423-g-man&quot;&gt;G-Man: J. Edgar Hoover and the Making of the American Century&lt;/a&gt; by Beverly Gage.  Wow this is a lot of J. Edgar Hoover info.  He was certainly a central figure in the 20th century.  A sobering story about the accumulation of power, and the abuse of power, by him and by politicians around him.  We are not well served by elected or appointed officials with long terms.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/42837514-gender-queer&quot;&gt;Gender Queer: A Memoir&lt;/a&gt; by Maia Kobabe.  An easy to read memoir, a good introduction to one person’s story about gender.  Much I don’t know about these issues.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/682681.She&quot;&gt;She: A History of Adventure&lt;/a&gt; by H. Rider Haggard. Been on my shelves for years, finally cracked it.  A rip roaring tale tho obviously hasn’t aged well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/52038578-blood-and-oil&quot;&gt;Blood and Oil: Mohammed bin Salman’s Ruthless Quest for Global Power&lt;/a&gt; by Bradley Hope and Justin Scheck.  Another blood boiler.  Very difficult to be positive about alliance with Saudi Arabia after reading this.  Also makes me even more pro-renewables so that we can stop dealing with these turds.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/259789.The_Blood_of_the_Lamb&quot;&gt;The Blood of the Lamb&lt;/a&gt; by Peter de Vries.  Oof, what a gut punch.  A man struggles for meaning and faith over the course of a life in which he loses his brother, first love, his wife, his parents, his daughter. And somehow de Vries injects levity in the story.  Great admiration for the writing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">G-Man: J. Edgar Hoover and the Making of the American Century by Beverly Gage. Wow this is a lot of J. Edgar Hoover info. He was certainly a central figure in the 20th century. A sobering story about the accumulation of power, and the abuse of power, by him and by politicians around him. We are not well served by elected or appointed officials with long terms. Gender Queer: A Memoir by Maia Kobabe. An easy to read memoir, a good introduction to one person’s story about gender. Much I don’t know about these issues. She: A History of Adventure by H. Rider Haggard. Been on my shelves for years, finally cracked it. A rip roaring tale tho obviously hasn’t aged well. Blood and Oil: Mohammed bin Salman’s Ruthless Quest for Global Power by Bradley Hope and Justin Scheck. Another blood boiler. Very difficult to be positive about alliance with Saudi Arabia after reading this. Also makes me even more pro-renewables so that we can stop dealing with these turds. The Blood of the Lamb by Peter de Vries. Oof, what a gut punch. A man struggles for meaning and faith over the course of a life in which he loses his brother, first love, his wife, his parents, his daughter. And somehow de Vries injects levity in the story. Great admiration for the writing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Idea roundups</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/roundups" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Idea roundups" /><published>2023-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/roundups</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/roundups">&lt;p&gt;Some useful roundups of ideas from around the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gurwinder.substack.com/p/40-useful-concepts-you-should-know&quot;&gt;40 useful concepts&lt;/a&gt;, hattip to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recomendo.com/p/recomendo-issue-340-23-01-18&quot;&gt;Recomendo&lt;/a&gt;.  So many pithy insights – “People just aren’t thinking about you that much.”, “By celebrating people for their intelligence, we make them stupid”, “Action creates traction, so each step you take will facilitate the next.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fatherly.com/life/questions-to-ask-dad-before-hes-gone&quot;&gt;12 questions to ask dad before he’s gone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bookfreak.substack.com/p/book-freak-103-bertrand-russells&quot;&gt;The Conquest of Happiness&lt;/a&gt; – seems like a book I should read.  “One of the symptoms of an approaching nervous breakdown is the belief that one’s work is terribly important.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/noahkagan/status/1628469491515392001&quot;&gt;The Law of 100&lt;/a&gt;.  Practice and repetition with feedback is the way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Some useful roundups of ideas from around the web.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – The Mountain In The Sea, Breakheart Pass, Nophek Gloss, Bad Mexicans</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/books" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – The Mountain In The Sea, Breakheart Pass, Nophek Gloss, Bad Mexicans" /><published>2023-02-11T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-02-11T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/books</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/books">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/59808603-the-mountain-in-the-sea&quot;&gt;The Mountain In The Sea&lt;/a&gt; by Ray Nayler.  Good introspective tale about discovery and creation of different kinds of intelligences. Octopi are fascinating.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/149607.Breakheart_Pass&quot;&gt;Breakheart Pass&lt;/a&gt; by Alistair MacLean.  As a kid I read all MacLean’s books and loved them.  As a lark I reread one.  OK it is overwritten, under-edited, a little trite – but there is a great story in the bones of this book, I understand why I ate them up.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/54539799-nophek-gloss&quot;&gt;Nophek Gloss&lt;/a&gt; by Essa Hansen.  I am not sure why I gave this book so much of a chance, it is a fairly typical hero saga with really dumb sci fi elements.  Not worth it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/61055606-bad-mexicans&quot;&gt;Bad Mexicans&lt;/a&gt; by Kelly Lytle Hernandez.  Chock full of history that I never learned, and I really should know, but the book is just boring.  Kept falling asleep.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Mountain In The Sea by Ray Nayler. Good introspective tale about discovery and creation of different kinds of intelligences. Octopi are fascinating. Breakheart Pass by Alistair MacLean. As a kid I read all MacLean’s books and loved them. As a lark I reread one. OK it is overwritten, under-edited, a little trite – but there is a great story in the bones of this book, I understand why I ate them up. Nophek Gloss by Essa Hansen. I am not sure why I gave this book so much of a chance, it is a fairly typical hero saga with really dumb sci fi elements. Not worth it. Bad Mexicans by Kelly Lytle Hernandez. Chock full of history that I never learned, and I really should know, but the book is just boring. Kept falling asleep.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Trust, The Future is History, China RX</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/trust" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Trust, The Future is History, China RX" /><published>2023-01-15T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-15T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/trust</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/trust">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/59039413-trust&quot;&gt;Trust&lt;/a&gt; by Hernan Diaz.  Worthy of all the accolades.  The truth is slowly unravelled as different characters relate their experience, stripping away facade after facade.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/35112020-the-future-is-history&quot;&gt;The Future Is History: How Totalitarianism Reclaimed Russia&lt;/a&gt; by Masha Gessen.  The story of the end of the Soviet Union and the rise of the current Russian goverment/society told thru the stories of people who endured it.  Very sobering assessment of Russian society and government, the enthusiasm for and commitment to totalitarianism runs deep.  Even more a supporter of a free Ukraine after reading this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/37492588-china-rx&quot;&gt;China Rx: Exposing the Risks of America’s Dependence on China for Medicine&lt;/a&gt; by Rosemary Gibson.  A little histrionic at times, and overly long and repetitive, but raises good issues.  There is a glaring hole in the recommendations, there is no way we can depend on inspections of manufacturing facilities in the US or overseas to ensure quality, we have to perform random sample testing of product in the field and take fast action based on problems identified.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Trust by Hernan Diaz. Worthy of all the accolades. The truth is slowly unravelled as different characters relate their experience, stripping away facade after facade. The Future Is History: How Totalitarianism Reclaimed Russia by Masha Gessen. The story of the end of the Soviet Union and the rise of the current Russian goverment/society told thru the stories of people who endured it. Very sobering assessment of Russian society and government, the enthusiasm for and commitment to totalitarianism runs deep. Even more a supporter of a free Ukraine after reading this. China Rx: Exposing the Risks of America’s Dependence on China for Medicine by Rosemary Gibson. A little histrionic at times, and overly long and repetitive, but raises good issues. There is a glaring hole in the recommendations, there is no way we can depend on inspections of manufacturing facilities in the US or overseas to ensure quality, we have to perform random sample testing of product in the field and take fast action based on problems identified.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I’m off twitter for now</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/bye-bye-twitter" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I’m off twitter for now" /><published>2022-12-18T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-18T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/bye-bye-twitter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/bye-bye-twitter">&lt;p&gt;Elon has every right to have whatever editorial policy he wants and to support whatever membership he wants.  It is his company.  And Twitter is not some special place, some sacred commons — it is just another media site, and like every media site, it is going to have a slant and a certain audience goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increasingly, the site doesn’t match with my interests.  It is becoming an outrage fest and Elon is encouraging that.  Elon posts provocative stuff, people express outrage, and other people express outrage about the outrage.  Elon isn’t the only driver of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is we are awash in tools to express ourselves, it has never been easier to get your voice out and connect with people.  I read and post on Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, Linkedin, Mastodon, Post, Goodreads, Discord, Wordpress, Github, and more.  I’ve considered and discarded so many alternatives, I can’t remember them all.  Social networks, microblogging platforms, short message platforms, video clip sharing services, photo sharing services, blogging tools, newsletter tools, website hosting, discussion forums, video hosting services — there are so many tools available and more every day.  I can’t keep up with them all, I have probably missed entire categories of tools.  And in every category there are multiple choices, with multiple different content policies.  There is a place for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter and its adherents don’t owe me anything and I don’t owe twitter or anyone on it a listen.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Elon has every right to have whatever editorial policy he wants and to support whatever membership he wants. It is his company. And Twitter is not some special place, some sacred commons — it is just another media site, and like every media site, it is going to have a slant and a certain audience goal.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recent Books – Sea of Tranquility, The Year of Peril, Overstory, Boys and Men, Sandworm, Fortune Favors the Dead</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/tranquility" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recent Books – Sea of Tranquility, The Year of Peril, Overstory, Boys and Men, Sandworm, Fortune Favors the Dead" /><published>2022-12-17T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/tranquility</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/tranquility">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/58446227-sea-of-tranquility&quot;&gt;Sea of Tranquility&lt;/a&gt; by Emily St. John Mandel.  What if our world really is just a simulation?  An OK tale but not a knockout.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/53499001-the-year-of-peril&quot;&gt;The Year of Peril: America in 1942&lt;/a&gt; by Tracy Campbell.  Interesting look at the stresses in American society in 1942.  We look back now and feel like our victory in WWII was inevitable and that all Americans pulled together.  Reality is much messier.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40180098-the-overstory&quot;&gt;The Overstory&lt;/a&gt; by Richard Powers.  I don’t get it.  Plodding.  Couldn’t be bothered to finish it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60613920-of-boys-and-men&quot;&gt;Of Boys and Men: Why the Modern Male Is Struggling, Why It Matters, and What to Do about It&lt;/a&gt; by Richard B. Reeves.  Very thought provoking.  This is not some apologist text about men, it is a very critical view of how we are raised and molded and demands that we do better.  It is also very critical of Democratic Party approaches to the issue.  The solutions are a little too straight line but worth reading.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41436213-sandworm&quot;&gt;Sandworm: A New Era of Cyberwar and the Hunt for the Kremlin’s Most Dangerous Hackers&lt;/a&gt; by Andy Greenberg.  I don’t know, just didn’t really grab me.  Something about the narrative was just kind of boring.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/50666983-fortune-favors-the-dead&quot;&gt;Fortune Favors the Dead&lt;/a&gt; by Stephen Spotswood.  Oh what a great detective story, two wonderful main characters in the Holmes/Watson tradition, vulnerable and very human.  Really liked it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Sea of Tranquility by Emily St. John Mandel. What if our world really is just a simulation? An OK tale but not a knockout. The Year of Peril: America in 1942 by Tracy Campbell. Interesting look at the stresses in American society in 1942. We look back now and feel like our victory in WWII was inevitable and that all Americans pulled together. Reality is much messier. The Overstory by Richard Powers. I don’t get it. Plodding. Couldn’t be bothered to finish it. Of Boys and Men: Why the Modern Male Is Struggling, Why It Matters, and What to Do about It by Richard B. Reeves. Very thought provoking. This is not some apologist text about men, it is a very critical view of how we are raised and molded and demands that we do better. It is also very critical of Democratic Party approaches to the issue. The solutions are a little too straight line but worth reading. Sandworm: A New Era of Cyberwar and the Hunt for the Kremlin’s Most Dangerous Hackers by Andy Greenberg. I don’t know, just didn’t really grab me. Something about the narrative was just kind of boring. Fortune Favors the Dead by Stephen Spotswood. Oh what a great detective story, two wonderful main characters in the Holmes/Watson tradition, vulnerable and very human. Really liked it.</summary></entry></feed>